<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSM Troubleshooting Information on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CSM Troubleshooting Information on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-12</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manual SSH Key Setting Process</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/bmc_ssh_key_manual_fixup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/bmc_ssh_key_manual_fixup/</guid>
      <description>Manual SSH Key Setting Process If for whatever reason this script fails, SSH keys can be set manually using the following process:&#xA;Save the public SSH key for the root user.&#xA;ncn# export SCSD_SSH_KEY=$(cat /root/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | sed &amp;#39;s/[[:space:]]*$//&amp;#39;) If a different SSH key is to be used (for example from conman) set the SCSD_SSH_KEY environment variable to that key value.&#xA;Generate a System Configuration Service configuration via the scsd tool. The admin must be authenticated to the Cray CLI before proceeding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot the CMS Barebones Image Boot Test</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/cms_barebones_image_boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/cms_barebones_image_boot/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot the CMS Barebones Image Boot Test Verify that the CSM services needed to boot a node are available and working properly. This section describes how the barebonesImageTest script works and how to interpret the results. If the script is unavailable, the manual steps for reproducing the Barebones image boot test are provided.&#xA;Topics 1. Steps the Script Performs 2. Controlling Which Node Is Used 3. Controlling Test Script Output Level 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running CT Tests Manually</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/hms_ct_manual_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/hms_ct_manual_run/</guid>
      <description>Running CT Tests Manually To run the tests manually:&#xA;ncn# /opt/cray/tests/ncn-resources/hms/hms-test/hms_run_ct_smoke_tests_ncn-resources.sh Examine the output. If one or more failures occur, investigate the cause of each failure. See the interpreting_hms_health_check_results documentation for more information.&#xA;Otherwise, run the HMS functional tests.&#xA;ncn# /opt/cray/tests/ncn-resources/hms/hms-test/hms_run_ct_functional_tests_ncn-resources.sh Examine the output. If one or more failures occur, investigate the cause of each failure. See the interpreting_hms_health_check_results documentation for more information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting HMS Health Check Results</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/interpreting_hms_health_check_results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/interpreting_hms_health_check_results/</guid>
      <description>Interpreting HMS Health Check Results Table of contents Introduction HMS smoke tests HMS functional tests Additional troubleshooting run_hms_ct_tests.sh smd_tavern_api_test_ncn-functional.sh smd_discovery_status_test_ncn-smoke.sh HTTPsGetFailed ChildVerificationFailed DiscoveryStarted Install blocking vs. Non-blocking failures Known issues Warning flags incorrectly set in HSM for Mountain BMCs BMCs set to On state in HSM ComponentEndpoints of Redfish subtype AuxiliaryController in HSM ComponentEndpoints with EthernetInterfaces named DE* in HSM Custom Roles and SubRoles for Components in HSM Resolved backup pod issues causing smoke test failures Introduction This document describes how to interpret the results of the HMS health check scripts and techniques for troubleshooting when failures occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PXE Booting Runbook</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/pxe_runbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/troubleshooting/pxe_runbook/</guid>
      <description>PXE Booting Runbook PXE booting is a key component of a working Shasta system. There are a lot of different components involved, which increases the complexity. This guide runs through the most common issues and shows what is needed in order to have a successful PXE boot.&#xA;NCNs on install ncn-m001 on reboot or NCN boot 2.1. Verify DHCP packets can be forwarded from the workers to the MTL network (VLAN1) 2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
