<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Admin Toolkit (SAT) on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Admin Toolkit (SAT) on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-16</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SAT Uninstall and Downgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/sat_uninstall_and_downgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/sat_uninstall_and_downgrade/</guid>
      <description>SAT Uninstall and Downgrade Uninstall: Remove a Version of SAT This procedure can be used to uninstall a version of SAT installed as a separate product stream. This is an optional procedure. Its main benefits are that it will free up a small amount of space in Nexus, and it may reduce confusion by removing additional outdated SAT versions from the cray-product-catalog Kubernetes ConfigMap.&#xA;This procedure cannot be used to uninstall the version of SAT included in the CSM release.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAT on an External System</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/sat_on_an_external_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/system_admin_toolkit/sat_on_an_external_system/</guid>
      <description>SAT on an External System The sat command-line utility can optionally be installed and configured on an external system to interact with CSM over the CAN.&#xA;Limitations Most sat commands work by accessing APIs which are reachable via the CAN. However, certain sat commands depend on host-based functionality on the management NCNs and will not work from an external system. This includes the following:&#xA;The platform-services and ncn-power stages of sat bootsys The local host information displayed by the --local option of sat showrev Installing the sat CLI on an external system is not an officially supported configuration.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
