<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Access Service (UAS) on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Access Service (UAS) on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-15</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add a Volume to UAS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/add_a_volume_to_uas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/add_a_volume_to_uas/</guid>
      <description>Add a Volume to UAS NOTE: UAS is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;This procedure registers and configures a volume in UAS so that the volume can be mounted in UAIs.&#xA;See List Volumes Registered in UAS for examples of valid volume configurations. Refer to Elements of a UAI for descriptions of the volume configuration fields and values.&#xA;Note the following caveats about adding volumes to UAS:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broker Mode UAI Management</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/broker_mode_uai_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/broker_mode_uai_management/</guid>
      <description>Broker Mode UAI Management NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;A Broker UAI is a special kind of UAI whose job is not to host users directly but to accept attempts to reach a UAI, locate or create a UAI for the user making the attempt, and then pass the user&amp;rsquo;s connection on to the correct UAI. Multiple Broker UAIs can be created, each serving users with UAIs of a different classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choosing UAI Resource Settings</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/choosing_uai_resource_settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/choosing_uai_resource_settings/</guid>
      <description>Choosing UAI Resource Settings NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;The Resource Specifications and UAI Classes sections describe how to set up resource specifications to be used with UAIs. Refer to those sections for all procedures and specific data structures associated with resources. In this section the question of how and why to configure UAI resources is addressed. While Kubernetes resource requests and limits can be used for other things, this section focuses on memory requests and limits and CPU requests and limits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common UAI Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/common_uai_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/common_uai_config/</guid>
      <description>Common UAI Configuration NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;This section provides guidance on common UAI configuration activities. Specific procedures and settings are covered elsewhere, but each topic provides links to the appropriate information as well as guidance on using that particular configuration.&#xA;Refer to the following configuration topics:&#xA;Choosing UAI Resource Settings Setting End-User UAI Timeouts Broker UAI Resiliency and Load Balancing Top: User Access Service (UAS)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure End-User UAI Classes for Broker Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_end-user_uai_classes_for_broker_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_end-user_uai_classes_for_broker_mode/</guid>
      <description>Configure End-User UAI Classes for Broker Mode NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Each UAI broker will create and manage a single class of End-User UAIs. A site using the Broker Mode of UAI management must create a Brokered End-User UAI Class for each distinct type of End-User UAI it wants served by a Broker UAI. Information on what should be configured for a Brokered End-User UAI Class can be found in UAI Classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure UAIs in UAS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_uais_in_uas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_uais_in_uas/</guid>
      <description>Configure UAIs in UAS NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;The sub-topics in this section cover the four main elements of UAI configuration in UAS, and provide Links to procedures for listing, adding, examining, updating, and deleting each kind of element.&#xA;Options for the elements of a UAI are maintained in the UAS configuration. The following can be configured in UAS:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Broker UAI Class</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_a_broker_uai_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_a_broker_uai_class/</guid>
      <description>Configure a Broker UAI Class NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Configuring a Broker UAI class consists of the following actions:&#xA;Create volumes to hold any site-specific authentication, SSH, or other configuration required Choose the End-User UAI class for which the Broker UAI will serve instances Create a UAI Class with (at a minimum): namespace set to uas default set to false volume_mounts set to the list of customization volume-ids created above public_ip set to true uai_compute_network set to false uai_creation_class set to the class-id of the End-User UAI class The basic contents of a Broker UAI Class is discussed in UAI Classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure a Default UAI Class for Legacy Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_a_default_uai_class_for_legacy_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/configure_a_default_uai_class_for_legacy_mode/</guid>
      <description>Configure a Default UAI Class for Legacy Mode NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Using a default UAI class is optional but recommended for any site using the legacy UAI management mode that wants to have some control over UAIs created by users. UAI classes used for this purpose need to have certain minimum configuration in them:&#xA;The image_id field set to identify the image used to construct UAIs The volume_list field set to the list of volumes to mount in UAIs The public_ip field set to true The uai_compute_network flag set to true (if workload management will be used) The default flag set to true to make this the default UAI class To make UAIs useful, there is a minimum set of volumes that should be defined in the UAS configuration:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create UAIs From Specific UAI Images in Legacy Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_uais_from_specific_uai_images_in_legacy_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_uais_from_specific_uai_images_in_legacy_mode/</guid>
      <description>Create UAIs From Specific UAI Images in Legacy Mode NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;A user can create a UAI from a specific UAI image (assuming no default UAI class exists) using a command of the form:&#xA;user&amp;gt; cray uas create --publickey &amp;lt;path&amp;gt; --imagename &amp;lt;image-name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;image-name&amp;gt; is the name shown above in the list of UAI images.&#xA;For example:&#xA;vers&amp;gt; cray uas images list default_image = &amp;#34;registry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai/</guid>
      <description>Create a UAI NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;The UAS allows either administrators or authorized users using the Legacy Mode of UAI management to create UAIs. This section shows both methods.&#xA;It is rare that an an administrator would hand-craft an End-User UAI using this administrative procedure, but it is possible. This is, however, the procedure used to create Broker UAIs for Broker Mode UAI Management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a UAI Class</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_class/</guid>
      <description>Create a UAI Class NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Add a new User Access Instance (UAI) class to the User Access Service (UAS) so that the class can be used to configure UAIs.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) Procedure Add a UAI class by using the command in the following example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a UAI Resource Specification</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_resource_specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_resource_specification/</guid>
      <description>Create a UAI Resource Specification NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Add a resource specification to UAS. Once added, a resource specification can be used to request or limit specific resource consumption on a host node or gain access to host node features managed by Kubernetes resources. The examples in this documentation focus on memory and CPU usage, but Kubernetes does use resources in some configurations to manage access to other kinds of resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a UAI with Additional Ports</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_with_additional_ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_a_uai_with_additional_ports/</guid>
      <description>Create a UAI with Additional Ports NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;In legacy mode UAI creation, an option is available to expose UAI ports to the customer user network in addition to the port used for SSH access. These ports are restricted to ports 80, 443, and 8888. This procedure allows a user or administrator to create a new UAI with these additional ports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create and Use Default UAIs in Legacy Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_and_use_default_uais_in_legacy_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/create_and_use_default_uais_in_legacy_mode/</guid>
      <description>Create and Use Default UAIs in Legacy Mode NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Create a UAI using the default UAI image or the default UAI class in legacy mode.&#xA;Procedure (user&amp;gt;) Create a UAI with a command of the following form:&#xA;cray uas create --public-key &amp;#39;&amp;lt;path&amp;gt;&amp;#39; &amp;lt;path&amp;gt; is the path to a file containing an SSH public-key matched to the SSH private key belonging to the user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize End-User UAI Images</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/customize_end-user_uai_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/customize_end-user_uai_images/</guid>
      <description>Customize End-User UAI Images NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;The provided end-user UAI image is a basic UAI image that includes an up-to-date version of the SLES Linux distribution. It provides an entry point to using UAIs and an easy way for administrators to experiment with UAS configurations. To support building software to be run in compute nodes, or other HPC and Analytics workflows, it is necessary to create a custom end-user UAI image and use that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the Broker UAI Image</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/customize_the_broker_uai_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/customize_the_broker_uai_image/</guid>
      <description>Customize the Broker UAI Image NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;The Broker UAI image that comes with UAS is the image used to construct Broker UAIs.&#xA;The key pieces of the Broker UAI image are:&#xA;An entrypoint shell script that initializes the container and starts the SSH daemon running. An SSH configuration that forces logged in users into the switchboard command which creates / selects End-User UAIs and redirects connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete a UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai/</guid>
      <description>Delete a UAI NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;There are two procedures described here. The first shows how an administrator can manually delete arbitrary UAIs or delete UAIs belonging to a given user or created using a given UAI Class. The second shows how an authorized user on can delete UAIs created in the legacy UIA creation mode.&#xA;When a UAI is deleted, any running WLM sessions associated with the owner of the UAI are left intact and can be interacted with through future UAIs owned by the same user or from UANs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete a UAI Class</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_class/</guid>
      <description>Delete a UAI Class NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Delete a UAI class. After deletion, the class will no longer be available for creation of UAIs. Existing UAIs are unaffected.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Class ID of the UAI Class to be deleted: List UAI Classes Procedure Delete a UAI Class by using a command of the following form:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete a UAI Image Registration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_image_registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_image_registration/</guid>
      <description>Delete a UAI Image Registration NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Unregister a UAI image from UAS.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the name of the UAI Image Registration to be deleted: List Registered UAI Images Procedure Deleting a UAI image from UAS removes the UAI image registration from UAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete a UAI Resource Specification</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_resource_specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_uai_resource_specification/</guid>
      <description>Delete a UAI Resource Specification NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Delete a specific UAI resource specification using the resource_id of that specification. Once deleted, UAIs will no longer be able to use that specification for creation. Existing UAIs are not affected by the change.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Resource ID of the resource specification to be deleted: List Resource Specifications Procedure To delete a particular resource specification, use a command of the following form:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delete a Volume Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_volume_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/delete_a_volume_configuration/</guid>
      <description>Delete a Volume Configuration NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Delete an existing volume configuration. This procedure does not delete the underlying object referred to by the UAS volume configuration.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Volume ID of the UAS volume to be deleted: List Volumes Registered in UAS Procedure Delete the target volume configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements of a UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/elements_of_a_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/elements_of_a_uai/</guid>
      <description>Elements of a UAI NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;All UAIs can have the following attributes associated with them:&#xA;A required container image An optional set of volumes An optional resource specification An optional collection of other configuration items This topic explains each of these attributes.&#xA;UAI container image The container image for a UAI (UAI image) defines and provides the basic environment available to the user.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>End-User UAIs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/end_user_uais/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/end_user_uais/</guid>
      <description>End-User UAIs NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;UAIs used for interactive logins are called End-User UAIs. End-User UAIs can be seen as lightweight User Access Nodes (UANs), but there are important differences between UAIs and UANs.&#xA;End-User UAIs are not dedicated hardware like UANs. They are implemented as containers orchestrated by Kubernetes, which makes them subject to Kubernetes scheduling and resource management rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examine a UAI Using a Direct Administrative Command</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/examine_a_uai_using_a_direct_administrative_command/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/examine_a_uai_using_a_direct_administrative_command/</guid>
      <description>Examine a UAI Using a Direct Administrative Command NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Print out information about a UAI.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway. The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host. The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized with cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legacy Mode User-Driven UAI Management</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/legacy_mode_user-driven_uai_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/legacy_mode_user-driven_uai_management/</guid>
      <description>Legacy Mode User-Driven UAI Management NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;In the legacy mode, users create and manage their own UAIs through the Cray CLI. A user may create, list, and delete only UAIs owned by the user. The user may not create a UAI for another user, nor may the user see or delete UAIs owned by another user. Once created, the information describing the UAI gives the user the information needed to reach the UAI using SSH and log into it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Available UAI Classes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_available_uai_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_available_uai_classes/</guid>
      <description>List Available UAI Classes NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;View all the details of every available UAI class. Use this information to select a class to apply to one or more UAIs.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) Procedure List all available UAI classes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Available UAI Images in Legacy Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_available_uai_images_in_legacy_mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_available_uai_images_in_legacy_mode/</guid>
      <description>List Available UAI Images in Legacy Mode NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;A user can list the UAI images available for creating a UAI with a command of the form:&#xA;user&amp;gt; cray uas images list For example:&#xA;vers&amp;gt; cray uas images list default_image = &amp;#34;registry.local/cray/cray-uai-sles15sp2:1.2.4&amp;#34; image_list = [ &amp;#34;registry.local/cray/cray-uai-sles15sp2:1.2.4&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;registry.local/cray/cray-uai-sanity-test:1.2.4&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;registry.local/cray/cray-uai-broker:1.2.4&amp;#34;,] Top: User Access Service (UAS)&#xA;Next Topic: Create UAIs From Specific UAI Images in Legacy Mode</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Registered UAI Images</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_registered_uai_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_registered_uai_images/</guid>
      <description>List Registered UAI Images NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Administrators can use the cray uas admin config images list command to see the list of registered images. This command also displays the UAS registration information about each image.&#xA;While Registering a UAI image name with UAS is necessary for UAIs to use the image, simply registering the image is not sufficient. The registered image must also be created and stored appropriately in its container registry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List UAI Resource Specifications</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uai_resource_specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uai_resource_specifications/</guid>
      <description>List UAI Resource Specifications NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Obtain a list of all the UAI resource specifications registered with UAS.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) Procedure List all the resource specifications registered in UAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List UAIs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uais/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uais/</guid>
      <description>List UAIs NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;There are two ways to list UAIs in UAS. One of these is an administrative action and provides access to all currently running UAIs. The other is associated with the Legacy UAI Management mode and provides authorized users access to their own UAIs. Both of these are shown here.&#xA;View the details of every UAI that is running by using a direct UAS administrative command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List UAS Version Information</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uas_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_uas_information/</guid>
      <description>List UAS Version Information NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Use the cray uas mgr-info list command to determine the version and service name of UAS.&#xA;List UAS Version with cray uas mgr-info list cray uas mgr-info list Example output:&#xA;service_name = &amp;#34;cray-uas-mgr&amp;#34; version = &amp;#34;1.16.1&amp;#34; Top: User Access Service (UAS)&#xA;Next-Topic: End-User UAIs</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>List Volumes Registered in UAS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_volumes_registered_in_uas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/list_volumes_registered_in_uas/</guid>
      <description>List Volumes Registered in UAS NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;List the details of all volumes registered in UAS with the cray uas admin config volumes list command. Use this command to obtain the volume_id value of volume, which is required for other UAS administrative commands.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) Procedure The volume registrations in the UAS configuration can be quite extensive and sometimes difficult to read in the default TOML format used by the cray administrative CLI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log in to a Broker UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/log_in_to_a_broker_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/log_in_to_a_broker_uai/</guid>
      <description>Log in to a Broker UAI NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;SSH to log into a Broker UAI and reach the End-User UAIs on demand.&#xA;Prerequisites The user must be logged into a host that can reach the external IP address of the Broker UAI The user must know the external IP address or DNS host name of the Broker UAI Procedure Log in to the Broker UAI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Page Has Moved</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/login_to_a_users_uai_to_troubleshoot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/login_to_a_users_uai_to_troubleshoot_issues/</guid>
      <description>This Page Has Moved The information on this page has moved to Troubleshoot UAIs with Administrative Access. Refer to that page for these procedures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modify a UAI Class</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/modify_a_uai_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/modify_a_uai_class/</guid>
      <description>Modify a UAI Class NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Update a UAI class with a modified configuration.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Class ID of the UAI Class to be modified: List UAI Classes Limitations The ID of the UAI class cannot be modified.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obtain the Configuration of a UAS Volume</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/obtain_configuration_of_a_uas_volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/obtain_configuration_of_a_uas_volume/</guid>
      <description>Obtain the Configuration of a UAS Volume NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;View the configuration information of a specific UAS volume. This procedure requires the volume_ID of that volume.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Volume ID of the volume to be retrieved: List Volumes Registered in UAS Procedure View the configuration of a specific UAS volume.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Register a UAI Image</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/register_a_uai_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/register_a_uai_image/</guid>
      <description>Register a UAI Image NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Register a UAI image with UAS. Registration tells UAS where to locate the image and whether to use the image as the default for UAIs.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The UAI image must be created and uploaded to the container registry: Customize End-User UAI Images Procedure Register a UAI image with UAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clear UAS Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/reset_the_uas_configuration_to_original_installed_settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/reset_the_uas_configuration_to_original_installed_settings/</guid>
      <description>Clear UAS Configuration NOTE: UAI is deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;WARNING: The procedure described here will remove all UAS configuration including some configuration that is installed upon installation / upgrade of the HPE Cray EX system. If this procedure is used, the update-uas Helm chart must be removed and re-deployed to restore the full HPE provided configuration. This procedure should only be used in an extreme situation where the UAS configuration has become corrupted to the point where it can no longer be managed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource Specifications</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/resource_specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/resource_specifications/</guid>
      <description>Resource Specifications NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Kubernetes uses resource limits and resource requests, to manage the system resources available to pods. Because UAIs run as pods under Kubernetes, UAS takes advantage of Kubernetes to manage the system resources available to UAIs.&#xA;In the UAS configuration, resource specifications contain that configuration. A UAI that is assigned a resource specification will use that instead of the default resource limits or requests on the Kubernetes namespace containing the UAI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve Resource Specification Details</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/retrieve_resource_specification_details/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/retrieve_resource_specification_details/</guid>
      <description>Retrieve Resource Specification Details NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6.&#xA;Display a specific resource specification using the resource_id of that specification.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Resource ID of the resource specification to be retrieved: List Resource Specifications Procedure Retrieve a resource specification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieve UAI Image Registration Information</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/retrieve_uai_image_registration_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/retrieve_uai_image_registration_information/</guid>
      <description>Retrieve UAI Image Registration Information NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Use this procedure to obtain the default and imagename values for a registered UAI image. This procedure can also be used to confirm that a specific image ID is still registered with UAS.&#xA;This procedure returns the same information as List Registered UAI Images, but only for one image.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting UAI Timeouts</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/setting_uai_timeouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/setting_uai_timeouts/</guid>
      <description>Setting UAI Timeouts NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;The procedures and specific values used for setting UAI timeouts are explained in the UAI Classes section. Please refer to that section.&#xA;On systems where UAIs are used as part of normal user activities, the number of UAIs can grow large. Stale UAIs (i.e. UAIs that sit idle for long periods of time) can prevent creation of fresh UAIs for users who are actually active on the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broker UAI Resiliency and Load Balancing</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/setting_up_multi-replica_brokers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/setting_up_multi-replica_brokers/</guid>
      <description>Broker UAI Resiliency and Load Balancing NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Broker UAI resiliency and load balancing is achieved through the use of Multi-Replica Broker UAIs. The procedures and data involved in configuring a UAI Class to create Multi-Replica Broker UAIs can be found in UAI Classes. This page describes some of the reasons to use Multi-Replica Broker UAIs and some of the implications of doing so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special Purpose UAIs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/special_purpose_uais/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/special_purpose_uais/</guid>
      <description>Special Purpose UAIs NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Even though most UAIs are End-User UAIs, UAI classes make it possible to construct UAIs to serve special purposes that are not strictly end-user oriented.&#xA;One kind of special purpose UAI is the Broker UAI, which provides on demand End-User UAI launch and management. While no other specialty UAI types currently exist, other applications are expected to arise and sites are encouraged to innovate as needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start a Broker UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/start_a_broker_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/start_a_broker_uai/</guid>
      <description>Start a Broker UAI NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Create a Broker UAI after a Broker UAI class has been created.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) There must be an appropriate Broker UAI Class defined: Configure a Broker UAI Class The administrator must know the Class ID of the desired Broker UAI Class: List UAI Classes Optional: the administrator may choose a site defined name for the Broker UAI to be used in conjunction with the HPE Cray EX System External DNS mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Broker UAI SSSD Cannot Use /etc/sssd/sssd.conf</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_broker_sssd_cant_use_sssd_conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_broker_sssd_cant_use_sssd_conf/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Broker UAI SSSD Cannot Use /etc/sssd/sssd.conf NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Symptom A Broker UAI has been created using an SSSD configuration in a secret and volume as described in Configure a Broker UAI Class, but logging into the Broker UAI does not work.&#xA;Diagnose the problem as follows:&#xA;Find the UAI name of the Broker UAI in a list of existing UAIs:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Common Mistakes when Creating a Custom End-User UAI Image</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_common_mistakes_when_creating_a_custom_end-user_uai_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_common_mistakes_when_creating_a_custom_end-user_uai_image/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Common Mistakes when Creating a Custom End-User UAI Image NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;There are several problems that may occur while making or working with custom end-user UAI images. The following are some basic troubleshooting questions to ask:&#xA;Does SESSION_NAME match an actual entry in cray bos v2 sessiontemplates list? Is the SESSION_ID set to an appropriate UUID format?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Duplicate Mount Paths in a UAI</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_duplicate_mount_paths_in_a_uai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_duplicate_mount_paths_in_a_uai/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Duplicate Mount Paths in a UAI NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;If a user attempts to create a UAI in the legacy mode and cannot create the UAI at all, a good place to look is at volumes. Duplicate mount_path specifications in the list of volumes in a UAI will cause a failure that looks like this:&#xA;ncn-m001-cray uas create --publickey ~/.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Missing or Incorrect UAI Images</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_missing_or_incorrect_uai_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_missing_or_incorrect_uai_images/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Missing or Incorrect UAI Images NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;If a UAI shows a uai_status of Waiting and a uai_msg of ImagePullBackOff, that indicates that the UAI or the UAI class is configured to use an image that is not in the image registry.&#xA;Either obtaining and pushing the image to the image registry, or correcting the name or version of the image in the UAS configuration will usually resolve this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Stale Brokered UAIs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_stale_brokered_uais/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_stale_brokered_uais/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Stale Brokered UAIs NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;When a Broker UAI terminates and restarts, the SSH key used to forward SSH sessions to End-User UAIs changes (this is a known problem) and subsequent Broker UAIs are unable to forward sessions to End-User UAIs. The symptom of this is that a user logging into a Broker UAI will receive a password prompt from the End-User UAI and be unable to log in even if providing the correct password.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAS / CLI Authentication Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uai_authentication_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uai_authentication_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAS / CLI Authentication Issues NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Several troubleshooting steps related to authentication in a UAI.&#xA;Internal Server Error An error was encountered while accessing Keycloak because of an invalid token.&#xA;cray uas create --publickey ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub Usage: cray uas create [OPTIONS] Try &amp;#34;cray uas create --help&amp;#34; for help. Error: Internal Server Error: An error was encountered while accessing Keycloak The uas-mgr logs show:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAI Stuck in ContainerCreating</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uai_stuck_in_containercreating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uai_stuck_in_containercreating/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAI Stuck in ContainerCreating NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Resolve an issue causing UAIs to show a uai_status field of Waiting, and a uai_msg field of ContainerCreating. It is possible that this is just a matter of starting the UAI taking longer than normal, perhaps as it pulls in a new UAI image from a registry. If the issue persists for a long time, it is worth investigating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAIs by Viewing Log Output</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uais_by_viewing_log_output/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uais_by_viewing_log_output/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAIs by Viewing Log Output NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Sometimes a UAI will come up and run but will not work correctly. It is possible to see errors reported by elements of the UAI entrypoint script using the kubectl logs command.&#xA;Procedure Find the UAI of interest.&#xA;This starts by identifying the UAI name using the CLI:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAIs with Administrative Access</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uais_with_administrative_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uais_with_administrative_access/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAIs with Administrative Access NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Sometimes there is no better way to figure out a problem with a UAI than to get inside it and look around as an administrator. This is done using kubectl exec to start a shell inside the running container as root (in the container). With this an administrator can diagnose problems, make changes to the running UAI, and find solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAS Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uas_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uas_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAS Issues NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;This section provides examples of some commands that can be used to troubleshoot UAS-related issues.&#xA;Troubleshoot Connection Issues packet_write_wait: Connection to 203.0.113.0 port 30841: Broken pipe If an error message related to broken pipes returns, enable keep-alives on the client side. The admin should update the /etc/ssh/sshd_config and /etc/ssh/ssh_config files to add the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAS by Viewing Log Output</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uas_by_viewing_log_output/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/troubleshoot_uas_by_viewing_log_output/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAS by Viewing Log Output NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;At times there will be problems with UAS. Usually this takes the form of errors showing up on CLI commands that are not immediately interpretable as some sort of input error. It is sometimes useful to examine the UAS service logs to find out what is wrong.&#xA;Procedure Find the names of the Kubernetes pods running UAS:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Classes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_classes/</guid>
      <description>UAI Classes NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;UAI Classes provide templates for the creation of UAIs. They permit precise configuration of the behavior, volumes, resources, and other elements of the UAI. When a UAI is created using a UAI Class, it is configured to use exactly what that UAI Class has in it at the time the UAI was created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Host Node Selection</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_host_node_selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_host_node_selection/</guid>
      <description>UAI Host Node Selection NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;When selecting UAI host nodes, it is a good idea to take into account the amount of combined load users and system services will bring to those nodes. UAIs run by default at a lower priority than system services on worker nodes which means that, if the combined load exceeds the capacity of the nodes, Kubernetes will eject UAIs and/or refuse to schedule them to protect system services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Host Nodes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_host_nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_host_nodes/</guid>
      <description>UAI Host Nodes NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;UAIs run as Kubernetes pods on Kubernetes worker nodes. UAS provides a a mechanism using Kubernetes labels to prevent UAIs from running on a specific worker nodes, but any Kubernetes node that is not labeled to prevent UAIs from running on it is considered eligible to host UAIs. The administrator of a given site may control the set of UAI host nodes by labeling Kubernetes worker nodes appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Image Customization</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_image_customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_image_customization/</guid>
      <description>UAI Image Customization NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;This section covers common customizations of both End-User UAIs and Broker UAIs.&#xA;Refer to the following topics for more information:&#xA;Customize the Broker UAI Image Customize End-User UAI Images Top: User Access Service (UAS)&#xA;Next Topic: Customize the Broker UAI Image</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Images</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_images/</guid>
      <description>UAI Images NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;There are three kinds of UAI images used by UAS:&#xA;A pre-packaged Broker UAI image provided with the UAS A pre-packaged basic End-User UAI Image provided with the UAS Custom End-User UAI images created on site, usually based on compute node contents UAS provides two stock UAI images when installed. The first is a standard End-User UAI Image that has the necessary software installed in it to support a basic Linux distribution login experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Management</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_management/</guid>
      <description>UAI Management NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;UAS supports two manual methods and one automated method of UAI management:&#xA;Direct administrative UAI management Legacy mode user driven UAI management UAI broker mode UAI management Direct administrative UAI management is available mostly to allow administrators to set up Broker UAIs for the Broker Mode UAI Management and to control UAIs that are created under one of the other two methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI Network Attachment Customization</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_network_attachments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_network_attachments/</guid>
      <description>UAI Network Attachment Customization NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;The UAI network attachment configuration flows from the Cray Site Initializer (CSI) localization data through customizations.yaml into the UAS Helm chart and, ultimately, into Kubernetes in the form of a &amp;ldquo;network-attachment-definition&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;This section describes the data at each of those stages to show how the final network attachment gets created. Customization of the network attachments may be needed by some sites to, for example, increase the size of the reserved sub-net used for UAI macvlan attachments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAI macvlans Network Attachments</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_macvlans_network_attachments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uai_macvlans_network_attachments/</guid>
      <description>UAI macvlans Network Attachments NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;UAIs need to be able to reach compute nodes across the HPE Cray EX internal networks. When the compute node networks are structured as multiple subnets, this requires routing from the UAIs to those subnets. The default route in a UAI goes to the public network through the Customer Access Network (CAN) so that will not work for reaching compute nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAS Limitations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uas_limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uas_limitations/</guid>
      <description>UAS Limitations NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Functionality that is currently not supported while using UAS.&#xA;Functionality Not Currently Supported by the User Access Service Lustre (lfs) commands within the UAS service pod Executing Singularity containers within the UAS service Building Docker containers within the UAS environment Building containerd containers within the UAS environment dmesg cannot run inside a UAI because of container security limitations Users cannot SSH from ncn-w001 to a UAI because UAIs use LoadBalancer IP addresses on the Customer Access Network (CAN) instead of NodePorts and the LoadBalancer IP addresses are not accessible from ncn-w001 Other Limitations There is a known issue where X11 traffic may not forward DISPLAY correctly if the user logs into an NCN node before logging into a UAI The cray uas uais commands are not restricted to operating on UAIs owned by the user authenticated with cray auth login Limitations Related To Restarts Changes made to a running UAI will be lost if the UAI is restarted or deleted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAS and UAI Legacy Mode Health Checks</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uas_and_uai_health_checks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/uas_and_uai_health_checks/</guid>
      <description>UAS and UAI Legacy Mode Health Checks NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Check the health of UAS and UAI to validate installation / upgrade of an HPE Cray EX system. This is a legacy mode procedure that can be run at installation / upgrade time to make sure that the following are true:&#xA;UAS is installed and running correctly UAI images are installed and registered correctly UAIs can be created in legacy mode Initialize and Authorize the CLI The procedures below use the CLI as an authorized user and run on two separate node types.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update a Resource Specification</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_resource_specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_resource_specification/</guid>
      <description>Update a Resource Specification NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Modify a specific UAI resource specification using the resource_id of that specification.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Resource ID of the resource specification to be updated: List UAI Resource Specifications Procedure To modify a particular resource specification, use a command of the following form:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update a UAI Image Registration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_uai_image_registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_uai_image_registration/</guid>
      <description>Update a UAI Image Registration NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Modify the UAS registration information of a UAI image.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Image ID of the UAI Image Registration to be updated: List UAI Registered Images Procedure Once a UAI image has been registered, it may be necessary to change its attributes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update a UAS Volume</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_uas_volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/update_a_uas_volume/</guid>
      <description>Update a UAS Volume NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Modify the configuration of an already-registered UAS volume. Almost any part of the configuration of a UAS volume can be modified.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know UAS volume ID of a volume; perform List Volumes Registered in UAS if needed The administrator should be familiar with Add a Volume to UAS; the options and caveats for updating volumes are the same as for creating volumes Procedure Modify the configuration of a UAS volume.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>View a UAI Class</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/view_a_uai_class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/view_a_uai_class/</guid>
      <description>View a UAI Class NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Display all the information for a specific UAI class by referencing its class ID.&#xA;Prerequisites The administrator must be logged into an NCN or a host that has administrative access to the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must have the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray command) installed on the above host The HPE Cray EX System CLI must be configured (initialized - cray init command) to reach the HPE Cray EX System API Gateway The administrator must be logged in as an administrator to the HPE Cray EX System CLI (cray auth login command) The administrator must know the Class ID of a UAI class: List Available UAI Classes Procedure View all the information about a specific UAI class.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volumes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/volumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/uas_user_and_admin_topics/volumes/</guid>
      <description>Volumes NOTE: UAS and UAI are deprecated in CSM 1.5.2 and will be removed in CSM 1.6&#xA;Volumes provide a way to connect UAIs to external data, whether they be Kubernetes managed objects, external file systems or files, host node files and directories, or remote networked data to be used within the UAI.&#xA;The following are examples of how volumes are commonly used by UAIs:&#xA;To connect UAIs to configuration files like /etc/localtime maintained by the host node To connect End-User UAIs to Slurm or PBS Professional Workload Manager configuration shared through Kubernetes To connect End-User UAIs to Programming Environment libraries and tools hosted on the UAI host nodes To connect End-User UAIs to Lustre or other external storage for user data To connect Broker UAIs to a directory service (see Configure a Broker UAI Class) or SSH configuration (see Customize the Broker UAI Image) needed to authenticate and redirect user sessions Any kind of volume recognized by the Kubernetes installation can be installed as a volume within UAS.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
