<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dns on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dns on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-16</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Domain Name Service (DNS) Overview</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/dns/</guid>
      <description>Domain Name Service (DNS) Overview DNS Architecture This diagram shows how the various components of the DNS infrastructure interact.&#xA;DNS Components The DNS infrastructure is comprised of a number of components.&#xA;Unbound (cray-dns-unbound) Unbound is a caching DNS resolver which is also used as the primary DNS server.&#xA;The DNS records served by Unbound include system component names (xnames), node hostnames, and service names. These records are read from the cray-dns-unbound ConfigMap which is populated by cray-dns-unbound-manager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable ncsd on UANs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/enable_ncsd_on_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/enable_ncsd_on_uans/</guid>
      <description>Enable ncsd on UANs Configure User Access Nodes (UANs) to start the ncsd service at boot time.&#xA;The nscd service is not currently enabled by default and systemd does not start it at boot time. There are two ways to start nscd on UAN nodes: manually starting the service or enabling the service in the UAN image. While restarting nscd manually has to be performed each time the UAN is rebooted, enabling nscd in the image only has to be done once.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage the DNS Unbound Resolver</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/manage_the_dns_unbound_resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/manage_the_dns_unbound_resolver/</guid>
      <description>Manage the DNS Unbound Resolver The unbound DNS instance is used to resolve names for the physical equipment on the management networks within the system, such as NCNs, UANs, switches, and compute nodes. This instance is accessible only within the HPE Cray EX system.&#xA;Check the status of the cray-dns-unbound pods Unbound logs View manager (DNS Helper) logs Restart Unbound Clear bad data in the Unbound ConfigMap Change the site DNS server Increase the number of Unbound pods Change which HSN NIC is used for the node alias Create custom DNS records Check the status of the cray-dns-unbound pods (ncn-mw#) Check the status of the pods:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerDNS Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/powerdns_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/powerdns_configuration/</guid>
      <description>PowerDNS Configuration External DNS PowerDNS replaces the CoreDNS server that earlier versions of CSM used to provide External DNS services.&#xA;The cray-dns-powerdns-can-tcp and cray-dns-powerdns-can-udp LoadBalancer resources are configured to service external DNS requests using the IP address specified by the CSI --cmn-external-dns command line argument.&#xA;The CSI --system-name and --site-domain command line arguments are combined to form the subdomain used for External DNS.&#xA;Site setup In the following example, the IP address 10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerDNS Migration Guide</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/powerdns_migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/powerdns_migration/</guid>
      <description>PowerDNS Migration Guide The migration to PowerDNS as the authoritative DNS source and the introduction of Bifurcated CAN (Customer Access Network) will result in some changes to the node and service naming conventions.&#xA;DNS Record Naming Changes Fully qualified domain names will be introduced for all DNS records.&#xA;Canonical name: hostname.network-path.system-name.site-domain&#xA;hostname - The hostname of the node or service network-path - The network path used to access the node .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Common DNS Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/troubleshoot_common_dns_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/troubleshoot_common_dns_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Common DNS Issues The Domain Name Service (DNS) is part of an integrated infrastructure set designed to provide dynamic host discovery, addressing, and naming. There are several different place to look for troubleshooting as DNS interacts with Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP), the Hardware Management Service (HMS), the System Layout Service (SLS), and the State Manager Daemon (SMD).&#xA;The information below describes what to check when experiencing issues with DNS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot PowerDNS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/troubleshoot_powerdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/dns/troubleshoot_powerdns/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot PowerDNS List DNS zone contents PowerDNS logging Verify DNSSEC operation Verify zones are being signed with the zone signing key Verify TSIG operation List DNS zone contents The PowerDNS zone database is populated with data from two sources:&#xA;The cray-powerdns-manager service creates the zones and DNS records based on data sourced from the System Layout Service (SLS). The external DNS records are populated by the cray-externaldns-external-dns service using data sourced from Kubernetes annotations and virtual service definitions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
