<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upgrade CSM on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upgrade CSM on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-16</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stage 0 - Prerequisites and Preflight Checks</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_0_prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_0_prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Stage 0 - Prerequisites and Preflight Checks Reminders:&#xA;CSM 1.5.0 or higher is required in order to upgrade to CSM 1.6. If any problems are encountered and the procedure or command output does not provide relevant guidance, see Relevant troubleshooting links for upgrade-related issues. Stage 0 has several critical procedures which prepare the environment and verify if the environment is ready for the upgrade.&#xA;Stage 0 - Prerequisites and Preflight Checks Start typescript Stage 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stage 1 - CSM Service Upgrades</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_1/</guid>
      <description>Stage 1 - CSM Service Upgrades Reminder: If any problems are encountered and the procedure or command output does not provide relevant guidance, see Relevant troubleshooting links for upgrade-related issues.&#xA;Start typescript Perform upgrade Verify Keycloak users Take Etcd Manual Backup Stop typescript Stage completed Start typescript (ncn-m001#) If a typescript session is already running in the shell, then first stop it with the exit command.&#xA;(ncn-m001#) Start a typescript.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stage 2 - Ceph image upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_2/</guid>
      <description>Stage 2 - Ceph image upgrade Reminder: If any problems are encountered and the procedure or command output does not provide relevant guidance, see Relevant troubleshooting links for upgrade-related issues.&#xA;Stage 2 - Ceph image upgrade Start typescript Argo workflows Storage node image upgrade and Ceph upgrade Stop typescript Stage completed Start typescript (ncn-m001#) If a typescript session is already running in the shell, then first stop it with the exit command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stage 3 - Kubernetes Upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/stage_3/</guid>
      <description>Stage 3 - Kubernetes Upgrade Reminder: If any problems are encountered and the procedure or command output does not provide relevant guidance, see Relevant troubleshooting links for upgrade-related issues.&#xA;Start typescript on ncn-m001 Stage 3.1 - Master node image upgrade Argo workflows Stage 3.2 - Worker node image upgrade Option 1 - Serial upgrade Option 2 - Parallel upgrade (Tech preview) Restrictions Example Stage 3.3 - ncn-m001 upgrade Stop typescript on ncn-m001 Backup artifacts on ncn-m001 Move to ncn-m002 Start typescript on ncn-m002 Prepare ncn-m002 Upgrade ncn-m001 Stage 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSM 1.5 to 1.6 Upgrade Process</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_management_nodes_and_csm_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_management_nodes_and_csm_services/</guid>
      <description>CSM 1.5 to 1.6 Upgrade Process Introduction This document guides an administrator through the upgrade of Cray Systems Management from version 1.5 to version 1.6. This procedure works for all patch versions of the source and target CSM releases.&#xA;This procedure is also the correct one to follow in the unusual situation of upgrading from a pre-release version of CSM 1.6.0 to a newer version of CSM 1.6.&#xA;When upgrading a system, follow this top-level file from top to bottom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade only CSM through IUF</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_only_csm_with_iuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_only_csm_with_iuf/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade only CSM through IUF This option describes how to upgrade Cray Systems Management (CSM) software on a CSM-only system using IUF.&#xA;CSM preparation&#xA;Read the Important Notes section of the CSM 1.5.0 or later to 1.6.0 Upgrade Process documentation and then follow only these CSM instructions in order:&#xA;Prepare for Upgrade Prepare for the upgrade procedure and download product media&#xA;Follow the IUF Prepare for the install or upgrade instructions to set environment variables used during the upgrade process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade only CSM</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_only_csm_without_iuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/upgrade_only_csm_without_iuf/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade only CSM This option describes how to upgrade Cray Systems Management (CSM) software on a CSM-only system without additional HPE Cray EX software products installed.&#xA;After the upgrade of CSM software, the CSM health checks will validate the system before doing any other operational tasks like the check and update of firmware on system components.&#xA;Prepare for upgrade Upgrade management nodes and CSM services Validate CSM health Check and update firmware Upgrade complete Note: If problems are encountered during the upgrade, some of the topics do have their own troubleshooting sections, but there is also a general troubleshooting topic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate CSM Health During a CSM Upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/validate_csm_health_during_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/validate_csm_health_during_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Validate CSM Health During a CSM Upgrade Before performing the health validation, be sure that at least 15 minutes have elapsed since the CSM services were upgraded. This allows the various Kubernetes resources to initialize and start. Although it is not recommended, the Booting CSM barebones image test may be skipped if all compute nodes are active running application workloads. (ncn-m002#) If a typescript session is already running in the shell, then first stop it with the exit command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prepare For Upgrade</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/prepare_for_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/upgrade/prepare_for_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Prepare For Upgrade Before beginning an upgrade to a new version of CSM, there are a few things to do on the system first.&#xA;Reduced resiliency during upgrade&#xA;[Preparation steps]&#xA;Start typescript Ensure latest documentation installed Export Nexus data Adding switch admin password to Vault Ensure SNMP is configured on the management network switches Running sessions Health validation Stop typescript Reduced resiliency during upgrade Warning: Management service resiliency is reduced during the upgrade.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
