<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management Network User Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management Network User Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-16</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manual Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/manual_switch_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/manual_switch_config/</guid>
      <description>Manual Switch Configuration Some of the switch configuration is not generated by CANU and needs to be manually applied.&#xA;Prerequisites The custom switch configuration is backed up. See Manual Switch Config.&#xA;SNMP Configuration For more information on SNMP credentials, see Configuring SNMP in CSM and Update Default Air-Cooled BMC and Leaf-BMC Switch SNMP Credentials&#xA;Once these credentials are retrieved from vault, fill in the xxxxxx fields below and paste the commands into the switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Install</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/fresh_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/fresh_install/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Install Use this procedure for either a first-time install or in the event a previous CSM was wiped and requires a new install.&#xA;Before continuing with install, make sure that CANU is running the most current version:&#xA;Install/Upgrade CANU&#xA;Procedure CAUTION: All of the following steps should be done using an out-of-band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;Upgrade switch firmware to specified firmware version.&#xA;Refer to Update Management Network Firmware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Added Hardware</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/added_hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/added_hardware/</guid>
      <description>Added Hardware Follow this procedure when new hardware is added to the system.&#xA;Procedure Validate the SHCD.&#xA;The SHCD defines the topology of a Shasta system, this is needed when generating switch configurations.&#xA;Refer to Validate the SHCD.&#xA;Generate the switch configuration file(s).&#xA;Refer to Generate Switch Configs.&#xA;Check the differences between the generated configurations and the configurations on the system.&#xA;Refer to Validate Switch Configs.&#xA;Run a suite of tests against the management network switches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/generate_switch_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/generate_switch_configs/</guid>
      <description>Generate Switch Configurations Generating configuration files can be done for a single switch or for the full system.&#xA;For example, if there is a suspected configuration issue on single switch, a configuration file can be generated for only that switch in order to simplify debugging.&#xA;Prerequisites CANU installed with 1.6.13 or later versions. Run canu --version to see version. If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply Custom Switch Configuration CSM 1.2</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config/</guid>
      <description>Apply Custom Switch Configuration CSM 1.2 Apply the backed up site connection configuration with a couple modifications. Since virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) is now used to separate customer traffic, the site ports and default routes must be added to that VRF.&#xA;Prerequisites Access to the switches&#xA;Custom switch configurations&#xA;Backup Custom Configuration Generated switch configurations already applied&#xA;Apply Switch Configurations Aruba Apply Configurations vrf attach Customer will be added to the port configuration that connects to the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/apply_switch_configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/apply_switch_configurations/</guid>
      <description>Apply Switch Configurations This process is generally straightforward and requires the user to copy and paste the generated switch configuration into the terminal.&#xA;All ports will be shutdown before applying switch configuration. If the port is in the SHCD and being used, it will be enabled when the configuration is applied.&#xA;There are some caveats that are mentioned below.&#xA;Prerequisites Switch without any configuration Wipe Management Switches Generated switch configurations Generate Switch Configuration Aruba Shutdown all ports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using canu-inventory with Ansible</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/canu_ansible_inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/canu_ansible_inventory/</guid>
      <description>Using canu-inventory with Ansible canu-inventory is a dynamic inventory script that queries a sls_input_file.json in the working directory, or an API gateway ($SLS_API_GW). It can be called directly to print the information or it can be passed as an argument to ansible-inventory.&#xA;$SLS_API_GW and $SLS_TOKEN (or $TOKEN) must be set in order to query the API. $SWITCH_USERNAME and $SWITCH_PASSWORD must be set in order to execute playbooks. ANSIBLE_HOST_KEY_CHECKING=False can be set to ignore host key checking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade CANU</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/canu_install_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/canu_install_update/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade CANU Prerequisite Before using the CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) to test, validate, or configure the network, ensure that CANU is running on the latest version.&#xA;CANU can be run from a personal workstation (the instructions below are targeted at Mac users), or on the Non-Compute Nodes (NCNs).&#xA;Since CANU is a Python application, it can be run on Linux and Mac, but the RPM is not currently designed to support multiple operating system environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collect Data</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/collect_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/collect_data/</guid>
      <description>Collect Data Collect the input data needed to generate switch configurations.&#xA;Prerequisites SSH access to the switches System Layout Service (SLS) API access Procedure Retrieve the most up-to-date SHCD spreadsheet. Accuracy in this spreadsheet is critical.&#xA;For example:&#xA;Internal repository Customer repository Get an SLS file from a Shasta system.&#xA;Log into any NCN where the Cray CLI is configured. Then run this command to create an SLS file named sls_file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Management</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/config_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/config_management/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management This page is designed for:&#xA;Showing users how initially save switch configurations so they can be used again. Switching between saved configurations. CAUTION All of these steps should be done using an out of band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;All this information can be found in the switch External User Guides.&#xA;Prerequisites It is recommended to do a show run on each switch and save that configuration before attempting the following procedures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring SNMP in CSM</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/configure_snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/configure_snmp/</guid>
      <description>Configuring SNMP in CSM This page describes how SNMP is used with CSM and provides some examples of working with SNMP on the management switches.&#xA;How SNMP is used in CSM Examples of configuring SNMP on management switches Dell SNMP Aruba SNMP Mellanox SNMP How SNMP is used in CSM The Prometheus SNMP Exporter, River Endpoint Discovery Service (REDS) hardware discovery, and Power Control Service (PCS)/Redfish Translation Service (RTS) management switch availability monitoring rely on SNMP credentials stored in Vault.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge switch cabling guide</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/edge_switch_cabling_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/edge_switch_cabling_guide/</guid>
      <description>Edge switch cabling guide This document helps network administrators and support personnel connect edge switch management network.&#xA;Quick Summary In some larger systems site connections are moved from spine to dedicated edge switches which allows for HSN (high speed network) to be cross connected allowing for alternative path to connect storage to customers site network.&#xA;Currently supported edge switch models:&#xA;Aruba 8325-32C 32 port 100G QSFP+/QSFP28 JL627A&#xA;Arista 7060CX2</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External User Guides</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/external_user_guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/external_user_guides/</guid>
      <description>External User Guides Refer to the following vendor-specific user guides for more information on Aruba, Dell, and Mellanox switches.&#xA;Aruba https://asp.arubanetworks.com/downloads Dell https://www.dell.com/support/manuals/en-us/force10-s4048-on/smartfabric-os-user-guide-10-5-1 Mellanox https://docs.nvidia.com/networking/spaces/viewspace.action?key=Onyxv393210 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Tests</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/network_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/network_tests/</guid>
      <description>Network Tests The CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) has the ability to run tests against the management network.&#xA;If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball. For more information, refer to the Update CANU From CSM Tarball procedure.&#xA;The switch inventory is dynamically created from either a System Layout Service (SLS) file --sls-file, or it will automatically query the SLS API if an SLS file is not specified.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinstall</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/reinstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/reinstall/</guid>
      <description>Reinstall Reinstall the same CSM version.&#xA;Before continuing with install, make sure that CANU is running the most current version:&#xA;Install/Upgrade CANU&#xA;CAUTION: All of these steps should be done using an out-of-band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;Procedure If the switches being reinstalled are already in the right CSM version, no configuration changes should be required.&#xA;Check the differences between generated configurations and the configurations on the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replace Switch</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/replace_switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/replace_switch/</guid>
      <description>Replace Switch CAUTION: Do not plug in a switch that is not configured. This can cause unpredictable behavior and network outages.&#xA;Prerequisites Out-of-band access to the switches (console). GA generated switch configuration or backed-up switch configuration exists. Generate Switch Configurations Configuration Management Procedure The following steps are required to replace a switch.&#xA;Update firmware on new switch.&#xA;See Update Management Network Firmware.&#xA;Apply the configuration.&#xA;See Apply Switch Configurations.&#xA;Unplug all the network and power cables and remove the failed switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Save a Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/saving_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/saving_config/</guid>
      <description>Save a Configuration Write Memory To keep track of what configuration version is running on the switch, create a new configuration file using the CSN version and the CANU version from the MOTD banner from the running config.&#xA;Mellanox Get the CSM and CANU versions from the MOTD banner.&#xA;sw-spine-001 [mlag-domain: master] (config) # show banner Example output:&#xA;Banners: Message of the Day (MOTD): ############################################################################### # CSM version: 1.0 # CANU version: 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus SNMP Exporter</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/snmp_exporter_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/snmp_exporter_configs/</guid>
      <description>Prometheus SNMP Exporter The Prometheus SNMP Exporter is deployed by the cray-sysmgmt-health chart to the sysmgmt-health namespace as part of the Cray System Management (CSM) release.&#xA;Adding SNMP credentials to the system Both the Prometheus SNMP Exporter and River Endpoint Discovery Service (REDS) hardware discovery use SNMP credentials stored in Vault. These credentials are read from Vault and pushed into customizations.yaml as a sealed secret. For the SNMP Exporter and REDS hardware discovery to work, three things need to have been done by an administrator:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transceivers and Cables</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/transceiver_cable_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/transceiver_cable_guide/</guid>
      <description>Transceivers and Cables The intent of this guide is to help administrators choose correct cabling and transceivers for Shasta management network. It is not intended to be a &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; guide on system cabling.&#xA;NOTE: Networking vendors may change supported devices or required software versions without notification.&#xA;Tips for navigating the cabling guide The supported transceivers are broken down by vendor and have direct links to vendor sites for more information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Example of the Connections Used in Shasta Management Network</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/transceiver_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/transceiver_example/</guid>
      <description>Example of the Connections Used in Shasta Management Network The intent of this guide is to give an example of which transceivers would typically be used in Shasta management network. Note that this example does not work in every scenario and is simply made to give an example of typical management network connections; they may or may not match how any specific setup.&#xA;This example covers a typical &amp;ldquo;full&amp;rdquo; topology setup with the following switches:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate Cabling</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_cabling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_cabling/</guid>
      <description>Validate Cabling Warning: If this step is completed when NCNs are offline or shutdown, the information compared here will not match the actual connections. Therefore, this step should be re-run again once the whole system is up.&#xA;To validate the cabling you can run command similar to below:&#xA;canu validate shcd-cabling --ips 10.252.0.2,10.252.0.3 --tabs 40G_10G --corners J12,T36 --shcd ./SHCD.xlsx NOTE Modify the command to use the correct SHCD file and correct --tabs, --corners, and IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate the SHCD</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_shcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_shcd/</guid>
      <description>Validate the SHCD Use the CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) to validate the Shasta Cabling Diagram (SHCD). SHCD validation is required to ensure that Plan of Record (PoR) network configurations are generated. This is an iterative process to create a model of the entire network topology connection by connection.&#xA;Topics Validate the SHCD Topics Prerequisites Validation steps Under the hood Check warnings Check SHCD port usage Logging and updates Prerequisites Up-to-date SHCD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_switch_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/validate_switch_configs/</guid>
      <description>Validate Switch Configurations Prerequisites SSH access to the switches or the running configuration file. Generated switch configurations. Generate Switch Configurations CANU installed with version 1.1.11 or greater. Run canu --version to see version. If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball. For more information, see this procedure: Update CANU From CSM Tarball Compare CSM 1.3 switch configurations with running configurations Compare the current running configuration with the generated configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wipe Management Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/wipe_mgmt_switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/wipe_mgmt_switches/</guid>
      <description>Wipe Management Switch Configuration This procedure describes how to wipe Aruba, Dell, and Mellanox switch configurations.&#xA;Prerequisites Out-of-band access to the switches (console)&#xA;Aruba (sw-spine-001#) Create a checkpoint before erasing the switch configuration.&#xA;More information related to backing up configuration can be found on the Configuration Management procedure.&#xA;copy running-config checkpoint CSM1_0 (sw-spine-001#)Verify the checkpoint was created.&#xA;show checkpoint Example output:&#xA;NAME TYPE WRITER DATE(YYYY/MM/DD) IMAGE VERSION CSM1_0 latest User 2022-01-27T18:52:31Z GL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aruba splitting of QSFP&#43; and QSFP28 ports</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/aruba_split_cables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/aruba_split_cables/</guid>
      <description>Aruba splitting of QSFP+ and QSFP28 ports Quad-SFP (QSFP+ and QSFP28) ports allow for four channels of lower-bandwidth communication.&#xA;AOS-CX release 10.05 introduced this feature for select switches and modules.&#xA;A QSFP+ 40G port can be split into four(4) 10G speed ports A QSFP28 100G port can be split into four(4) 25G speed ports Most QSFP28 ports can be used with either 40G or 100G optics, DAC or AOC cables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backup a Custom Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/backup_custom_configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/backup_custom_configurations/</guid>
      <description>Backup a Custom Configuration Prerequisites Access to the switches. If you are doing a fresh install of CSM but previously had a different version of CSM installed, then you will need to backup/restore certain switch configurations after the switch has been wiped.&#xA;The backup needs to be done before wiping the switch.&#xA;This includes:&#xA;Users and passwords SNMP credentials Site connections Interface speed commands Default routes Any other customized configuration for this system This configuration will likely vary from site to site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BICAN Support Matrix - Shasta Customer Access Networks</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_support_matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_support_matrix/</guid>
      <description>BICAN Support Matrix - Shasta Customer Access Networks Data sheet - Shasta networking - Customer Access Networks Overview Customer Access Networks (CANs) provide the interface between HPE Cray EX system networking and the customer site network. CANs are routed networks with broadcast domain separation. CANs provide higher availability and more flexibility in accessing cloud services compared to traditional &amp;ldquo;bastion hosts&amp;rdquo;, and are more in line with the cloud-native architecture of CSM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BICAN switch configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_switch_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_switch_configuration/</guid>
      <description>BICAN switch configuration Validate cabling and generate switch configurations for BICAN.&#xA;Cabling requirements Customer edge router is cabled to the HSN as described in the Slingshot documentation. Customer edge router is cabled to the management network. Below is an SHCD example of how the edge switches should be cabled to the management network. Note: the last line with the management ports will need to be excluded from CANU validate/generate. CANU currently does not support management ports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifurcating the CAN - Feature Details</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_details/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_details/</guid>
      <description>Bifurcating the CAN - Feature Details CAN new features overview Customer High Speed Network (CHN) Accessible CHN system ingress endpoints Accessible CHN system egress endpoints Endpoint naming Touchpoints: effects and changes When naming occurs Ability to change post-install Endpoint addressing Touchpoints: effects and changes When addressing occurs Ability to change post-install Traffic separation and routing Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post-install Customer Management Management Network (CMN) Traffic separation and routing Endpoint naming Endpoint addressing Changes Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post install Customer Access - external/site access Traffic separation and routing Changes Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post-install 1 CAN new features overview Bifurcation or splitting of the Customer Access Network (CAN) enables customization of customer traffic to and from the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BICAN Summary</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_summary/</guid>
      <description>BICAN Summary Bifurcated CAN was designed to separate administrative network traffic and user network traffic.&#xA;BICAN terminology BICAN – Bifurcated Customer Access Network CAN – Customer Access Network CMN – Customer Management Network CHN – Customer High Speed Network NMN – Node Management Network HMN – Hardware Management Network BICAN features Bifurcation or splitting of the Customer Access Network (CAN) enables customization of customer traffic to and from the system. Customization will be performed during installation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonded UAN Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bonded_uan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/bonded_uan/</guid>
      <description>Bonded UAN Configuration This document shows how to configure the management network when bonded UANs are used. These configurations should be implemented via the custom configuration feature in CANU. There are two ways to implement bonded UAN configuration.&#xA;25GB Bonded UAN Configuration (Most commonly used) The only difference between this configuration and the default configuration is that OCP &amp;amp; PCIe port 1 are in a bond. These connections are plugged into a spine (TDS) or leaf (FULL) switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cable Management Network Servers</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/cable_management_network_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/network/management_network/cable_management_network_servers/</guid>
      <description>Cable Management Network Servers This topic describes nodes in the air-cooled cabinet with diagrams and pictures showing where to find the ports on the nodes and how to cable the nodes to the management network switches.&#xA;HPE Hardware HPE DL385 HPE DL325 HPE Worker Node Cabling HPE Master Node Cabling HPE Storage Node Cabling HPE UAN Cabling HPE Apollo 6500 XL645D HPE Apollo 6500 XL675D Gigabyte/Intel Hardware Worker Node Cabling Master Node Cabling Storage Node Cabling UAN Cabling HPE Hardware HPE DL385 The OCP Slot is noted (number 7) in the image above.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
