<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSM product management on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CSM product management on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-10</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security Hardening</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/apply_security_hardening/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/apply_security_hardening/</guid>
      <description>Security Hardening This is an overarching guide to further harden the security posture of a Cray System Management (CSM) system.&#xA;If a subset of the steps in this procedure were completed as a consequence of an install, upgrade, or other guidance, then it is safe to skip that subset following a review.&#xA;Prerequisites None.&#xA;Procedure Change passwords and credentials.&#xA;Perform procedure(s) in Change Passwords and Credentials.&#xA;Restrict access to ncn-images S3 Bucket.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change Passwords and Credentials</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/change_passwords_and_credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/change_passwords_and_credentials/</guid>
      <description>Change Passwords and Credentials This is an overarching procedure to change all credentials managed by Cray System Management (CSM) in HPE Cray EX system to new values.&#xA;There are many passwords and credentials used in different contexts to manage the system. These can be changed as needed. Their initial settings are documented, so it is recommended to change them during or soon after a CSM software installation.&#xA;Prerequisites Review procedures in Manage System Passwords.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Keycloak Account</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/configure_keycloak_account/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/configure_keycloak_account/</guid>
      <description>Configure Keycloak Account Installation of CSM software includes a default account for administrative access to keycloak.&#xA;Depending on choices made during the installation, there may be a federated connection to an external Identity Provider (IdP), such as an LDAP or AD server, which enables the use of external accounts in keycloak.&#xA;However, if the external accounts are not available, then an &amp;ldquo;internal user account&amp;rdquo; could be created in keycloak. Having a usable account in keycloak with administrative authorization enables the use of the cray CLI for many administrative commands, such as those used to Validate CSM Health and general operation of the management services via the API gateway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure Non-Compute Nodes with CFS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/configure_non-compute_nodes_with_cfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/configure_non-compute_nodes_with_cfs/</guid>
      <description>Configure Non-Compute Nodes with CFS Non-compute node (NCN) personalization applies post-boot configuration to the HPE Cray EX management nodes. Several HPE Cray EX product environments outside of CSM require NCN personalization to function. Consult the manual for each product to configure them on NCNs by referring to the 1.5 HPE Cray EX System Software Getting Started Guide S-8000 on the HPE Customer Support Center.&#xA;This procedure defines the NCN personalization process for the CSM product using the Configuration Framework Service (CFS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perform NCN Personalization</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/perform_ncn_personalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/perform_ncn_personalization/</guid>
      <description>Perform NCN Personalization NCN personalization is the process of applying product-specific configuration to NCNs post-boot.&#xA;Prerequisites Prior to running this procedure, gather the following information required by CFS to create a configuration layer:&#xA;HTTP clone URL for the configuration repository in VCS Path to the Ansible play to run in the repository Commit ID in the repository for CFS to pull and run on the nodes Products may supply multiple plays to run, in which case multiple configuration layers must be created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-Install Customizations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/post_install_customizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/post_install_customizations/</guid>
      <description>Post-Install Customizations Post-install customizations may be needed as systems scale. These customizations also need to persist across future installs or upgrades. Not all resources can be customized post-install; common scenarios are documented in the following sections.&#xA;The following is a guide for determining where issues may exist, how to adjust the resources, and how to ensure the changes will persist. Different values may be be needed for systems as they scale.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redeploying a Chart</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/redeploying_a_chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/redeploying_a_chart/</guid>
      <description>Redeploying a Chart Administrators are able to customize many aspects of the system in order to address problems or tailor it to better suit their requirements. Often this requires redeploying one or more Helm charts. This page outlines the procedure for doing this in CSM. Other parts of the CSM documentation will reference this page if you are instructed to redeploy a chart. In those cases, the source page that links to this one should specify which charts should be redeployed and what customizations (if any) should be made to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remove Artifacts from Product Installations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/remove_artifacts_from_product_installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/remove_artifacts_from_product_installations/</guid>
      <description>Remove Artifacts from Product Installations Remove product artifacts that were imported from various Cray products. These instructions provide guidance for removing Image Management Service (IMS) images, IMS recipes, and Git repositories present in the Cray Product Catalog from the system.&#xA;The examples in this procedure show how to remove the product artifacts for the Cray System Management (CSM) product.&#xA;WARNING: If individual Cray products have removal procedures, those instructions supersede this procedure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate Signed RPMs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/validate_signed_rpms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-10/operations/csm_product_management/validate_signed_rpms/</guid>
      <description>Validate Signed RPMs The HPE Cray EX system signs RPMs to provide an extra level of security. Use the following procedure to import a key from either My HPE Software Center or a Kubernetes Secret, and then use that key to validate the RPM package signatures on each node type.&#xA;The RPMs will vary on compute, application, worker, master, and storage nodes. Check each node type to ensure the RPMs are correctly signed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
