<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>metallb bgp on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in metallb bgp on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-15</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check BGP Status and Reset Sessions</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/check_bgp_status_and_reset_sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/check_bgp_status_and_reset_sessions/</guid>
      <description>Check BGP Status and Reset Sessions Check the Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) status on the Aruba and Mellanox switches and verify that all sessions are in an Established state. If the state of any session in the table is Idle, then the BGP sessions must be reset.&#xA;Prerequisites Procedure Mellanox Aruba Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure The following procedures may not resolve the problem after just one attempt. In some cases, the procedures need to be followed multiple times before the situation resolves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MetalLB Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/metallb_configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/metallb_configuration/</guid>
      <description>MetalLB Configuration MetalLB provides a more robust configuration for the Node Management Network (NMNLB), Hardware Management Network (HMNLB), Customer Management Network (CMN), Customer High-Speed Network (CHN), and Customer Access Network (CAN). This configuration is generated from the csi config init input values.&#xA;MetalLB Peer Configuration The content for metallb_bgp_peers is generated by the csi config init command. In addition to the MetalLB configuration, there is configuration needed on the spine switches to set up the BGP router on these switches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MetalLB in BGP-Mode</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/metallb_in_bgp-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/metallb_in_bgp-mode/</guid>
      <description>MetalLB in BGP-Mode MetalLB is a component in Kubernetes that manages access to LoadBalancer services from outside the Kubernetes cluster. There are LoadBalancer services on the Node Management Network (NMNLB), Hardware Management Network (HMNLB), Customer Management Network (CMN), Customer High-Speed Network (CHN), and Customer Access Network (CAN).&#xA;MetalLB can run in either Layer 2 mode or BGP mode for each address pool it manages. BGP mode is used for the NMNLB, HMNLB, and CAN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot BGP not Accepting Routes from MetalLB</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/troubleshoot_bgp_not_accepting_routes_from_metallb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/troubleshoot_bgp_not_accepting_routes_from_metallb/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot BGP not Accepting Routes from MetalLB Check the number of routes that the Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) Router is accepting in the peering session. This procedure is useful if Kubernetes LoadBalancer services in the NMNLB, HMNLB, CMN, CHN or CAN address pools are not accessible from outside the cluster.&#xA;Regain access to Kubernetes LoadBalancer services from outside the cluster.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure Log into the spine or aggregate switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Services without an Allocated IP Address</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/troubleshoot_services_without_an_allocated_ip_address/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-15/operations/network/metallb_bgp/troubleshoot_services_without_an_allocated_ip_address/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Services without an Allocated IP Address Check if a given service has an IP address allocated for it if the Kubernetes LoadBalancer services in the NMNLB, HMNLB, CMN, CHN, or CAN address pools are not accessible from outside the cluster.&#xA;Regain access to Kubernetes LoadBalancer services from outside the cluster.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure Check the status of the services with the kubectl command to see the External-IP of the service.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
