<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Recovery on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Recovery on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-14</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PBS Service Recovery</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/pbs_service_recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/pbs_service_recovery/</guid>
      <description>PBS Service Recovery The following covers restoring PBS data.&#xA;Prerequisites The system is fully installed and has transitioned off of the LiveCD. All activities required for site maintenance are complete. A backup or export of the data already exists. Service recovery for PBS To restore PBS Professional data from backup, follow section 10.7.7 Restore PBS home directory from backup in the HPE Cray Programming Environment Installation Guide: CSM on HPE Cray EX Systems (S-8003).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slurm Service Recovery</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/slurm_service_recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/slurm_service_recovery/</guid>
      <description>Slurm Service Recovery The following covers restoring Slurm data.&#xA;Prerequisites The system is fully installed and has transitioned off of the LiveCD. All activities required for site maintenance are complete. A backup or export of the data already exists. Service recovery for Slurm To restore Slurm data from backup, follow sections 10.3.11 Restore Slurm Accounting Database from Backup and 10.3.13 Restore Slurm Spool Directory from Backup in the HPE Cray Programming Environment Installation Guide: CSM on HPE Cray EX Systems (S-8003).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beta Procedures for System Recovery</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/system_recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-14/operations/system_recovery/system_recovery/</guid>
      <description>Beta Procedures for System Recovery The table below provides links to the recovery procedures available for critical services.&#xA;Service Recovery procedures Vault Vault Service Recovery Keycloak Keycloak Service Recovery Spire Spire Service Recovery Nexus Nexus Service Recovery Slurm Slurm Service Recovery PBS PBS Service Recovery </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
