<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>boot orchestration on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in boot orchestration on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-16</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boot Orchestration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_api_versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_api_versions/</guid>
      <description>Boot Orchestration The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) currently supports API version v2. The following is a summary of the changes BOS v2 made from v1, and the upgrade path from v1 to v2.&#xA;BOS v1 removal BOS v1 is removed in CSM 1.6. During the upgrade to CSM 1.6, all BOS v1 session data is deleted. Other BOS data may be modified or, in rare cases, deleted. See BOS data notice for more details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Services</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_services/</guid>
      <description>BOS Services The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) consists of many different micro-services and other components, including the API, operators, and the BOS state reporter.&#xA;BOS API Boot Orchestration Agent (BOA) BOS operators actual-state-cleanup configuration discovery power-off-forceful power-off-graceful power-on session-cleanup session-completion session-setup status BOS state reporter BOS API The API is the point of contact for the user and all other services, including BOS&amp;rsquo; own services, that want to query or update BOS data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Workflows</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/bos_workflows/</guid>
      <description>BOS Workflows The following workflows present a high-level overview of common Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) operations. These workflows depict how services interact with each other when booting, configuring, or shutting down nodes. They also help provide a quicker and deeper understanding of how the system functions.&#xA;Terminology [Workflows] Boot nodes Reboot nodes Power off nodes Terminology The following are mentioned in the workflows:&#xA;Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) is responsible for booting, configuring, and shutting down collections of nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom Node Console or Logs Indicate that the Server Response has Timed Out</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_issue_symptom_node_console_or_logs_indicate_that_the_server_response_has_timed_out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_issue_symptom_node_console_or_logs_indicate_that_the_server_response_has_timed_out/</guid>
      <description>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom: Node Console or Logs Indicate that the Server Response has Timed Out If the TFTP request is able to access the TFTP service pod but is unable to find its way back to the node, it may be because the kernel is not tracking established TFTP connections.&#xA;Symptoms Problem detection Resolution Symptoms The following image is tcpdump data from within the TFTP pod. It shows what happens when the TFTP request cannot find a route back to the node that sent the request.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot Issue Symptom Node HSN Interface Does Not Appear or Show Detected Links Detected</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_issue_symptom_node_hsn_interface_does_not_appear_or_shows_no_link_detected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_issue_symptom_node_hsn_interface_does_not_appear_or_shows_no_link_detected/</guid>
      <description>Boot Issue Symptom: Node HSN Interface Does Not Appear or Show Detected Links Detected A node may fail to boot if the HSN interface is experiencing issues, or if it is not able to detect any links.&#xA;Symptom The node&amp;rsquo;s HSN interface does not appear in the output of the ip addr command or the output of the ethtool interface command shows no link detected.&#xA;Resolution Reseat the node&amp;rsquo;s PCIe card.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot Orchestration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_orchestration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_orchestration/</guid>
      <description>Boot Orchestration The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) is responsible for booting, configuring, and shutting down collections of nodes.&#xA;The currently supported API version for BOS is v2. BOS v2 relies on a number of permanent operators to guide components through state transitions in an independent manner. For more information, see BOS Workflows.&#xA;BOS users create BOS session templates via the REST API. A session template is a collection of metadata for a group of nodes and their desired boot artifacts and configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot UANs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_uans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/boot_uans/</guid>
      <description>Boot UANs Boot UANs with an image so that they are ready for user logins.&#xA;Prerequisites UAN boot images and a BOS session template have been created. See Create UAN Boot Images.&#xA;Procedure (ncn-mw#) Create a BOS session to boot the UAN nodes.&#xA;cray bos v2 sessions create --template-name uan-sessiontemplate-PRODUCT_VERSION \ --operation reboot --format json | tee session.json Example output:&#xA;{ &amp;#34;components&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;limit&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;9fea7f3f-0a77-40b9-892d-37712de51d65&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;operation&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;boot&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;stage&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;end_time&amp;#34;: null, &amp;#34;error&amp;#34;: null, &amp;#34;start_time&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2022-08-22T14:44:27&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;status&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;pending&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;template_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;cle-1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Commands Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>BOS Commands Cheat Sheet This page is a quick reference for common BOS commands in the Cray CLI.&#xA;To find the API versions of any commands listed, add -vvv to the end of the CLI command, and the CLI will print the underlying call to the API in the output.&#xA;Full system commands (ncn-mw#) Boot all nodes in a template:&#xA;cray bos v2 sessions create --template-name SESSION_TEMPLATE_NAME --operation boot (ncn-mw#) Reboot all nodes in a template:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Component Status</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/component_status/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/component_status/</guid>
      <description>Component Status For each component, BOS tracks information on what actions are expected to be happening (the phase) and what actions have recently happened (the last_action). This information is then aggregated into an overall status.&#xA;Phases Last actions Status Status transitions Phases A component&amp;rsquo;s phase is the high level part of the boot process that the component is currently on. This value is automatically monitored and set by the status operator based on the components desired and current state in BOS, the components power state as reported by HSM, and the component&amp;rsquo;s configuration status as reported by CFS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Components</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/components/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/components/</guid>
      <description>BOS Components BOS v2 provides a components endpoint where BOS tracks the status of individual components. This includes information on the desired state and some information on the current state, status, and any session the component is part of.&#xA;Component records are created automatically and will include any components found in the Hardware State Manager (HSM).&#xA;BOS component fields actual_state desired_state staged_state enabled error event_stats last_action session status Managing BOS components List all components Show details for a component Update a component BOS component fields actual_state Stores information on what BOS believes is the current boot artifacts the component is booted with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom Duplicate Address Warnings and Declined DHCP Offers in Logs</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_duplicate_address_warnings_and_declined_dhcp_offers_in_logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_duplicate_address_warnings_and_declined_dhcp_offers_in_logs/</guid>
      <description>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom: Duplicate Address Warnings and Declined DHCP Offers in Logs If the DHCP and node logs show duplicate address warnings and indicate declined DHCP offers, it may be because another component owns the IP address that DHCP is trying to assign to a node. If this happens, the node will not accept the IP address and will repeatedly submit a DHCP discover request. As a result, the node and DHCP become entangled in a loop of requesting and rejecting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom Message About Invalid EEPROM Checksum in Node Console or Log</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_message_about_invalid_eeprom_checksum_in_node_console_or_log/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_message_about_invalid_eeprom_checksum_in_node_console_or_log/</guid>
      <description>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom: Message About Invalid EEPROM Checksum in Node Console or Log On rare occasions, the processor hardware may lose the Serial Over Lan (SOL) connections and may need to be reseated to allow the node to successfully boot.&#xA;Symptoms This issue can be identified if the following is displayed in the node&amp;rsquo;s console or log:&#xA;console.38:2018-09-08 04:54:51 [ 16.721165] ixgbe 0000:18:00.0: The EEPROM Checksum Is Not Valid console.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom Node is Not Able to Download the Required Artifacts</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_node_is_not_able_to_download_the_required_artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_issue_symptom_node_is_not_able_to_download_the_required_artifacts/</guid>
      <description>Compute Node Boot Issue Symptom: Node is Not Able to Download the Required Artifacts If either or both of the kernel or the initrd boot artifacts are missing from the artifact repository, Boot Script Service (BSS), or both, the node will not be able to download the required boot artifacts and will fail to boot.&#xA;Symptoms The node&amp;rsquo;s console or log will display lines beginning with, &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;Could not start download&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. Refer to the image below for an example of this error message.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compute Node Boot Sequence</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/compute_node_boot_sequence/</guid>
      <description>Compute Node Boot Sequence Provides an overview of the compute node boot process and touches upon the fact that issues can be encountered during this process.&#xA;The following is a high-level overview of the boot sequence for compute nodes:&#xA;The compute node is powered on.&#xA;The BIOS issues a DHCP discover request.&#xA;DHCP responds with the following:&#xA;next-server, which is the IP address of the TFTP server. The name of the file to download from the TFTP server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Session Template to Boot Compute Nodes with CPS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/create_a_session_template_to_boot_compute_nodes_with_cps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/create_a_session_template_to_boot_compute_nodes_with_cps/</guid>
      <description>Create a Session Template to Boot Compute Nodes with CPS When compute nodes are booted, the Content Projection Service (CPS) and Data Virtualization Service (DVS) project the root file system (rootfs) over the network to the compute nodes by default.&#xA;Another option when compute nodes are booted is to download their rootfs into RAM.&#xA;This page covers the appropriate contents for a BOS session template in order to use CPS and DVS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Session Template to Boot Compute Nodes with Scalable Boot Projection Service (SBPS)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/create_a_session_template_to_boot_compute_nodes_with_sbps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/create_a_session_template_to_boot_compute_nodes_with_sbps/</guid>
      <description>Create a Session Template to Boot Compute Nodes with Scalable Boot Projection Service (SBPS) When compute nodes are booted, the Scalable Boot Projection Service (SBPS) projects the root file system (rootfs) over the network to the compute nodes using iSCSI.&#xA;This page covers the necessary configuration of a BOS session template in order to use SBPS.&#xA;Boot set rootfs_provider parameter Boot set rootfs_provider_passthrough parameter Setting the parameter Detailed Explanation &amp;lt;transport&amp;gt; &amp;lt;schema version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;IQN Domain&amp;gt; &amp;lt;DNS SRV record reference&amp;gt; &amp;lt;client discovery timeout in seconds&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ramroot&amp;gt; Example rootfs_provider_passthrough Example session template input file Appendix: root= kernel parameter The Scalable Boot Projection Service (SBPS) is the default provider for the rootfs on compute nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize iPXE Binary Names</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/customize_ipxe_binary_names/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/customize_ipxe_binary_names/</guid>
      <description>Customize iPXE Binary Names The default behavior for the cray-ipxe service is to build iPXE binaries with a well known name. However, to help prevent untrusted access to the iPXE binaries, sites may manually customize the iPXE binary names to a site-specific value. The site may further change the iPXE binary names periodically to further obfuscate and prevent access.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure Edit the cray-ipxe-settings ConfigMap using one of the following options.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determine Which BOS Session Booted a Node</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/determine_which_bos_session_booted_a_node/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/determine_which_bos_session_booted_a_node/</guid>
      <description>Determine Which BOS Session Booted a Node Overview Ask BOS to describe the component. The session that last acted upon the node is listed in this description.&#xA;Instructions (ncn-mw#) Set an environment variable to the xname of the node in question.&#xA;For example:&#xA;export NODE_XNAME=&amp;#34;x3000c0s17b0n0&amp;#34; (ncn-mw#) Query the BOS component for that node.&#xA;BOS_SESSION_ID=$(cray bos v2 components describe $NODE_XNAME --format json | jq -r .session) echo $BOS_SESSION_ID The output will be the BOS session ID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edit the iPXE Embedded Boot Script</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/edit_the_ipxe_embedded_boot_script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/edit_the_ipxe_embedded_boot_script/</guid>
      <description>Edit the iPXE Embedded Boot Script Manually adjust the iPXE embedded boot script to change the order of network interfaces for DHCP request. Changing the order of network interfaces for DHCP requests helps improve boot time performance.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure (ncn-mw#) Edit the ConfigMap using one of the following options.&#xA;NOTE Save a backup of the ConfigMap before making any changes.&#xA;The following is an example of creating a backup:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exporting and Importing BOS Data</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/exporting_and_importing_bos_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/exporting_and_importing_bos_data/</guid>
      <description>Exporting and Importing BOS Data Prerequisites Automated procedures Export Import Manual procedures Export Import Prerequisites Ensure that the cray command line interface (CLI) is authenticated and configured to talk to system management services. See Configure the Cray CLI. In order to use the automated procedures, the latest CSM documentation RPM must be installed on the node where the procedure is being performed. See Check for latest documentation. Automated procedures BOS data can be backed up using an automated script.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exporting and Importing BSS Data</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/exporting_and_importing_bss_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/exporting_and_importing_bss_data/</guid>
      <description>Exporting and Importing BSS Data Prerequisites Export BSS boot parameters Restore BSS boot parameters Prerequisites Ensure that the cray command line interface (CLI) is authenticated and configured to talk to system management services. See Configure the Cray CLI. In order to use the automated procedures, the latest CSM documentation RPM must be installed on the node where the procedure is being performed. See Check for latest documentation. Export BSS boot parameters (ncn-mw#) Create a JSON file with the boot parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Compute Node Boot Process</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/healthy_compute_node_boot_process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/healthy_compute_node_boot_process/</guid>
      <description>Healthy Compute Node Boot Process In order to investigate node boot-related issues, it is important to understand the flow of a healthy boot process and the associated components. This section outlines the normal flow of components that play a role in booting compute nodes, including DHCP, BSS, and TPTP.&#xA;DHCP A healthy DHCP exchange between server and client looks like the following:&#xA;Traffic Description Sender DHCP Discover A broadcast request from the client requesting an IP address.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Boot Parameters</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/kernel_boot_parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/kernel_boot_parameters/</guid>
      <description>Kernel Boot Parameters The Image Management Service (IMS) extracts kernel boot parameters from the /boot/kernel-parameters file in the image, if that file exists, and stores them in S3. IMS already stores the other boot artifacts (kernel, initrd, and rootfs) in S3. When told to boot an image, the Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) will extract these parameters and deliver them to the Boot Script Service (BSS) so they can be used during the next boot of a node.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Limit the Scope of a BOS Session</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/limit_the_scope_of_a_bos_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/limit_the_scope_of_a_bos_session/</guid>
      <description>Limit the Scope of a BOS Session The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) supports an optional limit parameter when creating a session. This parameter can be used to further limit the nodes that BOS runs against, and is applied to all boot sets.&#xA;If the session_limit_required BOS Option is enabled, then the limit parameter is not optional when creating a session.&#xA;The limit parameter takes a comma-separated list of nodes, groups, or roles in any combination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log File Locations and Ports Used in Compute Node Boot Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/log_file_locations_and_ports_used_in_compute_node_boot_troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/log_file_locations_and_ports_used_in_compute_node_boot_troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Log File Locations and Ports Used in Compute Node Boot Troubleshooting This section includes the port IDs and log file locations of components associated with the node boot process.&#xA;Log File Locations The log file locations for ConMan, DHCP, and TFTP.&#xA;ConMan logs are located within the conman pod at /var/log/conman.log.&#xA;DHCP:&#xA;kubectl logs DHCP_POD_ID TFTP:&#xA;kubectl logs -n services TFTP_POD_ID Port IDs The following table includes the port IDs for DHCP and TFTP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage a BOS Session</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/manage_a_bos_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/manage_a_bos_session/</guid>
      <description>Manage a BOS Session Once a Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) session template is created, users can perform operations on nodes, such as boot, reboot, and shutdown.&#xA;To find the API versions of any commands listed, add -vvv to the end of the CLI command, and the CLI will print the underlying call to the API in the output.&#xA;Create a new session List all sessions Show details for a session Delete a session Create a new session Creating a new BOS session requires the following command-line options:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage a Session Template</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/manage_a_session_template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/manage_a_session_template/</guid>
      <description>Manage a Session Template A session template must be created before starting a session with the Boot Orchestration Service (BOS).&#xA;This page shows Cray CLI commands for managing BOS session templates. To find the API versions of any commands listed, add -vvv to the end of the CLI command, and the CLI will print the underlying call to the API in the output.&#xA;Session template framework Create a session template List all session templates View a session template Delete a session template Session template framework When creating a new BOS session template, it can be helpful to start with a framework and then edit it as needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-tenancy with BOS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/multi_tenancy_with_bos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/multi_tenancy_with_bos/</guid>
      <description>Multi-tenancy with BOS BOS v2 supports multi-tenancy, allowing multiple tenants to coexist on a system with access to only their own separate resources. For more information on multi-tenancy see the Multi-Tenancy Overview For systems without tenants, this functionality can be ignored.&#xA;Tenant administrators Tenant administrators should be able to view their components, session templates and sessions normally. They will not be able to view the resources of another tenant, and will have restricted or no access to some BOS endpoints such the components endpoint which can be viewed but not patched, and the options endpoint which is blocked entirely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node Boot Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/node_boot_root_cause_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/node_boot_root_cause_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Node Boot Root Cause Analysis The first step in debugging compute node boot-related issues is to determine the underlying cause and the stage that the issue was encountered at.&#xA;BOS v2 provides rich, per-component records for underlying actions that have been applied as part of BOS session provisioning. Often, it is helpful to observe the set of operations that BOS has enacted on behalf of a session as they apply to a single failing node.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Options</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/options/</guid>
      <description>BOS Options BOS v2 provides a global service options endpoint for modifying the base configuration of the service itself.&#xA;Viewing the current option values Updating the option values BOS options details Viewing the current option values View the options with the following command:&#xA;(ncn-mw#)&#xA;cray bos v2 options list --format json Example output:&#xA;{ &amp;#34;cfs_read_timeout&amp;#34;: 20, &amp;#34;cleanup_completed_session_ttl&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;7d&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;clear_stage&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;component_actual_state_ttl&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;4h&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;default_retry_policy&amp;#34;: 3, &amp;#34;disable_components_on_completion&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;discovery_frequency&amp;#34;: 300, &amp;#34;ims_errors_fatal&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;ims_images_must_exist&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;logging_level&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;DEBUG&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;max_boot_wait_time&amp;#34;: 1200, &amp;#34;max_component_batch_size&amp;#34;: 1800, &amp;#34;max_power_off_wait_time&amp;#34;: 300, &amp;#34;max_power_on_wait_time&amp;#34;: 120, &amp;#34;polling_frequency&amp;#34;: 15, &amp;#34;reject_nids&amp;#34;: false, &amp;#34;session_limit_required&amp;#34;: false } Updating the option values The values for all BOS global options can be modified with the cray bos v2 options update command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redeploy the iPXE and TFTP Services</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/redeploy_the_ipxe_and_tftp_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/redeploy_the_ipxe_and_tftp_services/</guid>
      <description>Redeploy the iPXE and TFTP Services Redeploy the iPXE and TFTP services if a pod with a ceph-fs Process Virtualization Service (PVS) on a Kubernetes worker node is causing a HEALTH_WARN error.&#xA;Resolve issues with ceph-fs and ceph-mds by restarting the iPXE and TFTP services. The Ceph cluster will return to a healthy state after this procedure.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Procedure (ncn-mw#) Find the iPXE and TFTP deployments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rolling Upgrades using BOS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/rolling_upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/rolling_upgrades/</guid>
      <description>Rolling Upgrades using BOS NOTE This feature is the replacement for the Compute Rolling Upgrade Service (CRUS). CRUS was deprecated in CSM 1.2.0 and removed in CSM 1.5.0. See Deprecated Features.&#xA;BOS v2 allows users to stage boot artifacts, configuration, and an operation such as a reboot. The workload manager can later trigger the operation through BOS to apply that staged information, allowing rolling updates when nodes have no job running on them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Session Templates</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/session_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/session_templates/</guid>
      <description>BOS Session Templates Session templates in the Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) are a reusable collection of boot, configuration, and component information. After creation they can be combined with a boot operation to create a BOS session that will apply the desired changes to the specified components. Session templates can be created via the API by providing JSON data or via the CLI by writing the JSON data to a file, which can then be referenced using the --file parameter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOS Sessions</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/sessions/</guid>
      <description>BOS Sessions The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) creates a session when it is asked to perform an operation on a session template. Sessions provide a way to track the status of many nodes at once as they perform the same operation with the same session template information. When creating a session, both the operation and session template are required parameters.&#xA;BOS v2 supports these operations:&#xA;Reboot - Reboot a designated collection of nodes into the desired state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Staging Changes with BOS</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/stage_changes_with_bos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/stage_changes_with_bos/</guid>
      <description>Staging Changes with BOS In v2 of the Boot Orchestration Service (BOS), it is possible to stage changes when creating a session. These changes will not immediately take effect, and will instead be applied when the applystaged endpoint is called.&#xA;Creating a staged session Applying a staged state Stage changes without BOS Stage boot artifacts Stage a configuration Creating a staged session (ncn-mw#) Creating a staged session is no different than creating a normal session, with one exception: the staged value should be set to True.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools for Resolving Compute Node Boot Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/tools_for_resolving_boot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/tools_for_resolving_boot_issues/</guid>
      <description>Tools for Resolving Compute Node Boot Issues A number of tools can be used to analyze and debug issues encountered during the compute node boot process. The underlying issue and symptoms dictate the type of tool required.&#xA;BOS BOS component records offer a history of operations that have been applied to a node.&#xA;cray bos components describe x3000c0s19b4n0 Additionally, nodes that are unable to boot may also be disabled. BOS will not apply power actions to disabled nodes, allowing an administrator to debug the node environment interactively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_dynamic_host_configuration_protocol_dhcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_dynamic_host_configuration_protocol_dhcp/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) DHCP issues can result in node boot failures. This procedure helps investigate and resolve such issues.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges. kubectl is installed. Limitations Encryption of compute node logs is not enabled, so the passwords may be passed in clear text.&#xA;Procedure Log in to a non-compute node (NCN) as root.&#xA;(ncn-mw#) Check that the DHCP service is running.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Trivial File Transfer Protocol (TFTP)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_trivial_file_transfer_protocol_tftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_trivial_file_transfer_protocol_tftp/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Trivial File Transfer Protocol (TFTP) TFTP issues can result in node boot failures. Use this procedure to investigate and resolve such issues.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.&#xA;Limitations Encryption of compute node logs is not enabled, so the passwords may be passed in clear text.&#xA;Procedure (ncn-mw#) Check that the TFTP service is running.&#xA;kubectl get pods -n services -o wide | grep cray-tftp Start a tcpdump session on the NCN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Unified Extensible Firmware Interface (UEFI)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_unified_extensible_firmware_interface_uefi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_unified_extensible_firmware_interface_uefi/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to Unified Extensible Firmware Interface (UEFI) If a node is stuck in the UEFI shell, ConMan will be able to connect to it, but nothing else will appear in its logs. The node&amp;rsquo;s logs will look similar to the following, indicating that ConMan is updating its log hourly:&#xA;&amp;lt;ConMan&amp;gt; Console [86] log at 2018-09-07 20:00:00 CDT. &amp;lt;ConMan&amp;gt; Console [86] log at 2018-09-07 21:00:00 CDT. &amp;lt;ConMan&amp;gt; Console [86] log at 2018-09-07 22:00:00 CDT.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to the Boot Script Service (BSS)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_the_boot_script_service_bss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_related_to_the_boot_script_service_bss/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Related to the Boot Script Service (BSS) Boot Script Service (BSS) delivers a boot script to a node based on its MAC address. This boot script tells the node where to obtain its boot artifacts, which include:&#xA;kernel initrd In addition, the boot script also contains the kernel boot parameters. This procedure helps resolve issues related to missing boot artifacts.&#xA;Prerequisites This procedure requires administrative privileges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Using Kubernetes</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_using_kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_compute_node_boot_issues_using_kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot Compute Node Boot Issues Using Kubernetes A number of Kubernetes commands can be used to debug issues related to the node boot process. All of the traffic bound for the DHCP server, TFTP server, and Boot Script Service (BSS) is sent on the Node Management Network (NMN).&#xA;In the current arrangement, all three services are located on a management non-compute node (NCN). Thus, traffic must first travel through the NCN to reach these services inside their pods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/troubleshoot_uan_boot_issues/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshoot UAN Boot Issues Use this topic to guide troubleshooting of User Access Node (UAN) boot issues.&#xA;[UAN boot process](#uan-boot process) PXE issues initrd (dracut) issues Image boot issues UAN boot process The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) boots UANs. BOS uses session templates to define various parameters such as:&#xA;Which nodes to boot Which image to boot Kernel parameters Whether to perform post-boot configuration of the nodes by the Configuration Framework Service (CFS); this is also referred to as Node Personalization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upload Node Boot Information to Boot Script Service (BSS)</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/upload_node_boot_information_to_boot_script_service_bss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/upload_node_boot_information_to_boot_script_service_bss/</guid>
      <description>Upload Node Boot Information to Boot Script Service (BSS) The following information must be uploaded to BSS as a prerequisite to booting a node via iPXE:&#xA;The location of an initrd image in the artifact repository The location of a kernel image in the artifact repository Kernel boot parameters The nodes associated with that information, using either host name or node ID (NID) BSS manages the iPXE boot scripts that coordinate the boot process for nodes, and it enables basic association of boot scripts with nodes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>View the Status of a BOS Session</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/view_the_status_of_a_bos_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-16/operations/boot_orchestration/view_the_status_of_a_bos_session/</guid>
      <description>View the Status of a BOS Session The Boot Orchestration Service (BOS) supports a status endpoint that reports detailed status information for individual BOS sessions.&#xA;BOS session status View the status of a session Session status details BOS session status BOS session status offers an overall status, as well as information about the percentage of components in each state, and any errors being experienced. Status will be current as long as the session is running, and will cache itself when the session ends for future reference.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
