<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>system configuration service on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/</link>
    <description>Recent content in system configuration service on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-13</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure BMC and Controller Parameters with SCSD</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/configure_bmc_and_controller_parameters_with_scsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/configure_bmc_and_controller_parameters_with_scsd/</guid>
      <description>Configure BMC and Controller Parameters with SCSD The System Configuration Service (SCSD) allows administrators to set various BMC and controller parameters for components in liquid-cooled cabinets. These parameters are typically set during discovery, but this tool enables parameters to be set before or after discovery. The operations to change these parameters are available in the cray CLI under the scsd command.&#xA;The parameters which can be set are:&#xA;SSH key NTP server Syslog server BMC/Controller passwords SSH console key IMPORTANT: If the scsd tool is used to update the SSHConsoleKey value outside of ConMan, it will disrupt the ConMan connection to the console and collection of console logs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manage Parameters with the scsd Service</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/manage_parameters_with_the_scsd_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/manage_parameters_with_the_scsd_service/</guid>
      <description>Manage Parameters with the scsd Service The System Configuration Service commands below enable administrators to set various BMC and controller parameters. These parameters are controlled with the scsd command in the Cray CLI.&#xA;Retrieve Current Information from Targets Get the network protocol parameters (NTP/syslog server, SSH keys) and boot order for the targets in the payload. All fields are only applicable to Liquid Cooled controllers. Attempts to set them for Air Cooled BMCs will be ignored, and retrieving them for Air Cooled BMCs will return empty strings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set BMC Credentials Using SAT</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/set_bmc_credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/set_bmc_credentials/</guid>
      <description>Set BMC Credentials Using SAT Redfish BMCs are installed on the system with default credentials. After the machine is shipped, all BMC credentials must be changed.&#xA;BMC credentials may be set with either the System Configuration Service (SCSD), or with the System Admin Toolkit&amp;rsquo;s (SAT) sat bmccreds command. Both methods enable administrators to set a unique value for each credential, or to set the same value for every credential.&#xA;This procedure describes how to set BMC credentials with sat bmccreds, which conveniently automates the steps of the SCSD procedure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Configuration Service</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/system_configuration_service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/system_configuration_service/system_configuration_service/</guid>
      <description>System Configuration Service The System Configuration Service (SCSD) allows administrators to set various BMC and controller parameters. These parameters are typically set during discovery, but this tool enables parameters to be set before or after discovery. The operations to change these parameters are available in the Cray CLI under the scsd command.&#xA;The following are the parameters that most commonly must be set:&#xA;SSH keys IMPORTANT: If the scsd tool is used to update the SSHConsoleKey value outside of ConMan, it will disrupt the ConMan connection to the console and collection of console logs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
