<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management Network User Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management Network User Guide on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-12</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Management Network 1.0 (1.2 Preconfig) to 1.2</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/1.0_to_1.2_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/1.0_to_1.2_upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Management Network 1.0 (1.2 Preconfig) to 1.2 Prerequisites Mellanox Mellanox Manual Configuration Dell Dell Manual Configuration Aruba Spine Aruba Manual Configuration Aruba Leaf and Leaf BMC Prerequisites System is already running with CANU-generated 1.0 configurations (1.2 Preconfig). Generated switch configurations for 1.2. Generate Switch Configurations CANU installed with version 1.1.11 or greater. Run canu --version to see version. If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Load Saved Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/load_saved_switch_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/load_saved_switch_config/</guid>
      <description>Load Saved Switch Configuration This procedure is intended for internal use only.&#xA;This procedure switches between already saved switch configurations. It is used to quickly switch between configurations that are already loaded on the switches.&#xA;To save switch configurations, refer to the Configuration Management procedure.&#xA;When switching between configurations, the procedure must be followed on all management switches.&#xA;Spine switches have three total configuration files/checkpoints.&#xA;1.2 fresh install 1.2 upgrade 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Install</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/fresh_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/fresh_install/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Install Use this procedure for either a first-time install or in the event a previous CSM was wiped and requires a new install.&#xA;Before continuing with install, make sure that CANU is running the most current version:&#xA;Install/Upgrade CANU&#xA;Procedure CAUTION: All of the following steps should be done using an out-of-band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;Upgrade switch firmware to specified firmware version.&#xA;Refer to Update Management Network Firmware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Added Hardware</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/added_hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/added_hardware/</guid>
      <description>Added Hardware Follow this procedure when new hardware is added to the system.&#xA;Procedure Validate the SHCD.&#xA;The SHCD defines the topology of a Shasta system, this is needed when generating switch configurations.&#xA;Refer to Validate the SHCD.&#xA;Generate the switch configuration file(s).&#xA;Refer to Generate Switch Configs.&#xA;Check the differences between the generated configurations and the configurations on the system.&#xA;Refer to Validate Switch Configs.&#xA;Run a suite of tests against the management network switches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manual Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/manual_switch_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/manual_switch_config/</guid>
      <description>Manual Switch Configuration Some of the switch configuration is not generated by CANU and needs to be manually applied.&#xA;Prerequisites The custom switch configuration is backed up. See Manual Switch Config.&#xA;SNMP Configuration SNMP is currently only used on sw-leaf-bmc switches, these credentials can be retrieved from Vault. More information on SNMP credentials can be found in the Change SNMP Credentials on Leaf-BMC Switches procedure.&#xA;Once these credentials are retrieved from vault, fill in the xxxxxx fields below and paste the commands into the switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/generate_switch_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/generate_switch_configs/</guid>
      <description>Generate Switch Configurations Generating configuration files can be done for a single switch or for the full system.&#xA;For example, if there is a suspected configuration issue on single switch, a configuration file can be generated for only that switch in order to simplify debugging.&#xA;Prerequisites CANU installed with 1.1.11 or later versions. Run canu --version to see version. If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply Custom Switch Configurations for CSM 1.0</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config_1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config_1.0/</guid>
      <description>Apply Custom Switch Configurations for CSM 1.0 Apply the backed up site connection configuration with a couple modifications. Since virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) is now used to separate customer traffic, the site ports and default routes must be added to that VRF.&#xA;Prerequisites Access to the switches Custom switch configurations Backup Custom Configurations Generated switch configurations already applied Apply Switch Configurations Aruba apply configurations sw-spine-001# conf t interface 1/1/36 no shutdown description to:CANswitch_cfcanb6s1-31:from:sw-25g01_x3000u39-j36 ip address 10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply Custom Switch Configuration CSM 1.2</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config_1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_custom_config_1.2/</guid>
      <description>Apply Custom Switch Configuration CSM 1.2 Apply the backed up site connection configuration with a couple modifications. Since virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) is now used to separate customer traffic, the site ports and default routes must be added to that VRF.&#xA;Prerequisites Access to the switches&#xA;Custom switch configurations&#xA;Backup Custom Configuration Generated switch configurations already applied&#xA;Apply Switch Configurations Aruba apply configurations vrf attach Customer will be added to the port configuration that connects to the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_switch_configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/apply_switch_configurations/</guid>
      <description>Apply Switch Configurations This process is generally straightforward and requires the user to copy and paste the generated switch configuration into the terminal.&#xA;All ports will be shutdown before applying switch configuration. If the port is in the SHCD and being used, it will be enabled when the configuration is applied.&#xA;There are some caveats that are mentioned below.&#xA;Prerequisites Switch without any configuration Wipe Management Switches Generated switch configurations Generate Switch Configuration Aruba Shutdown all ports.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade CANU</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/canu_install_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/canu_install_update/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade CANU Prerequisite Before using the CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) to test, validate, or configure the network, ensure that CANU is running on the latest version.&#xA;CANU can be run from a personal workstation (the instructions below are targeted at Mac users), or on the Non-Compute Nodes (NCNs).&#xA;Since CANU is a Python application, it can be run on Linux and Mac, but the RPM is not currently designed to support multiple operating system environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collect Data</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/collect_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/collect_data/</guid>
      <description>Collect Data Collect the input data needed to generate switch configurations.&#xA;Prerequisites SSH access to the switches System Layout Service (SLS) API access Procedure Retrieve the most up-to-date SHCD spreadsheet. Accuracy in this spreadsheet is critical.&#xA;For example:&#xA;Internal repository Customer repository Get an SLS file from a Shasta system.&#xA;Log into any NCN where the Cray CLI is configured. Then run this command to create an SLS file named sls_file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Management</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/config_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/config_management/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Management This page is designed for:&#xA;Showing users how initially save switch configurations so they can be used again. Switching between saved configurations. CAUTION All of these steps should be done using an out of band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;All this information can be found in the switch External User Guides.&#xA;Prerequisites It is recommended to do a show run on each switch and save that configuration before attempting the following procedures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure SNMP</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/configure_snmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/configure_snmp/</guid>
      <description>Configure SNMP SNMP configuration is required for hardware discovery of the HPE Cray EX system.&#xA;These are examples only; verify SNMP credentials before applying this configuration.&#xA;For more information on SNMP credentials, see Change SNMP Credentials on Leaf-BMC Switches and Update Default Air-Cooled BMC and Leaf-BMC Switch SNMP Credentials.&#xA;Dell SNMP sw-leaf-bmc-001# conf t snmp-server group cray-reds-group 3 noauth read cray-reds-view snmp-server user testuser cray-reds-group 3 auth md5 xxxxxxxx priv des xxxxxxx snmp-server view cray-reds-view 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>External User Guides</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/external_user_guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/external_user_guides/</guid>
      <description>External User Guides Refer to the following vendor-specific user guides for more information on Aruba, Dell, and Mellanox switches.&#xA;Aruba https://asp.arubanetworks.com/downloads Dell https://www.dell.com/support/manuals/en-us/force10-s4048-on/smartfabric-os-user-guide-10-5-1 Mellanox https://docs.nvidia.com/networking/spaces/viewspace.action?key=Onyxv393210 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Tests</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/network_tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/network_tests/</guid>
      <description>Network Tests The CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) has the ability to run tests against the management network.&#xA;If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball. For more information, refer to the Update CANU From CSM Tarball procedure.&#xA;The switch inventory is dynamically created from either a System Layout Service (SLS) file --sls-file, or it will automatically query the SLS API if an SLS file is not specified.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinstall</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/reinstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/reinstall/</guid>
      <description>Reinstall Reinstall the same CSM version.&#xA;Before continuing with install, make sure that CANU is running the most current version:&#xA;Install/Upgrade CANU&#xA;CAUTION: All of these steps should be done using an out-of-band connection. This process is disruptive and will require downtime.&#xA;Procedure If the switches being reinstalled are already in the right CSM version, no configuration changes should be required.&#xA;Check the differences between generated configurations and the configurations on the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replace Switch</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/replace_switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/replace_switch/</guid>
      <description>Replace Switch CAUTION: Do not plug in a switch that is not configured. This can cause unpredictable behavior and network outages.&#xA;Prerequisites Out-of-band access to the switches (console). GA generated switch configuration or backed-up switch configuration exists. Generate Switch Configurations Configuration Management Procedure The following steps are required to replace a switch.&#xA;Update firmware on new switch.&#xA;See Update Management Network Firmware.&#xA;Apply the configuration.&#xA;See Apply Switch Configurations.&#xA;Unplug all the network and power cables and remove the failed switch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Save a Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/saving_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/saving_config/</guid>
      <description>Save a Configuration Write Memory To keep track of what configuration version is running on the switch, create a new configuration file using the CSN version and the CANU version from the MOTD banner from the running config.&#xA;Mellanox Get the CSM and CANU versions from the MOTD banner.&#xA;sw-spine-001 [mlag-domain: master] (config) # show banner Example output:&#xA;Banners: Message of the Day (MOTD): ############################################################################### # CSM version: 1.0 # CANU version: 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus SNMP Exporter</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/snmp_exporter_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/snmp_exporter_configs/</guid>
      <description>Prometheus SNMP Exporter The Prometheus SNMP Exporter is deployed by the cray-sysmgmt-health chart to the sysmgmt-health namespace as part of the Cray System Management (CSM) release.&#xA;Configuration In order to provide data to the Grafana SNMP dashboards, the SNMP Exporter must be configured with a list of management network switches to scrape metrics from.&#xA;This procedure assumes that this is being done as part of a CSM install as part of the Prepare site-init procedure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade Switches From 1.0 to 1.2 Preconfig</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Upgrade Switches From 1.0 to 1.2 Preconfig Use the following procedure to upgrade switches from 1.0 to 1.2 preconfig.&#xA;To check if the management network is using generated switch configurations, log onto a management switch and check for a banner with a CANU version. This indicates the switch configuration has been generated.&#xA;############################################################################### # CSM version: 1.0 # CANU version: 1.1.10 ############################################################################### To upgrade from CSM 1.2 preconfig (switch configurations generated) to CSM 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate Cabling</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_cabling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_cabling/</guid>
      <description>Validate Cabling Warning: If this step is completed when NCNs are offline or shutdown, the information compared here will not match the actual connections. Therefore, this step should be re-run again once the whole system is up.&#xA;To validate the cabling you can run command similar to below:&#xA;canu validate shcd-cabling --shcd ./SHCD.xlsx --tabs 40G_10G --corners J12,T36 --ips 10.252.0.2,10.252.0.3 NOTE: Modify the command to use the correct SHCD file and correct --tabs, --corners, and IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate the SHCD</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_shcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_shcd/</guid>
      <description>Validate the SHCD Use the CSM Automatic Network Utility (CANU) to validate the Shasta Cabling Diagram (SHCD). SHCD validation is required to ensure that Plan of Record (PoR) network configurations are generated. This is an iterative process to create a model of the entire network topology connection by connection.&#xA;Topics Prerequisites before validating the SHCD Begin validation in the following order Checks and Validations Logging and Updates Output SHD to JSON Prerequisites Up to date SHCD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validate Switch Configurations</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_switch_configs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/validate_switch_configs/</guid>
      <description>Validate Switch Configurations Prerequisites SSH access to the switches or the running configuration file. Generated switch configurations. Generate Switch Configurations CANU installed with version 1.1.11 or greater. Run canu --version to see version. If doing a CSM install or upgrade, a CANU RPM is located in the release tarball. For more information, see this procedure: Update CANU From CSM Tarball Compare CSM 1.2 switch configurations with running configurations Compare the current running configuration with the generated configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wipe Management Switch Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/wipe_mgmt_switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/wipe_mgmt_switches/</guid>
      <description>Wipe Management Switch Configuration This procedure describes how to wipe Aruba, Dell, and Mellanox switch configurations.&#xA;Prerequisites Out-of-band access to the switches (console)&#xA;Aruba Create a checkpoint before erasing the switch configuration.&#xA;More information related to backing up configuration can be found on the Configuration Management procedure.&#xA;sw-spine-001# copy running-config checkpoint CSM1_0 Verify the checkpoint was created.&#xA;sw-spine-001# show checkpoint Example output:&#xA;NAME TYPE WRITER DATE(YYYY/MM/DD) IMAGE VERSION CSM1_0 latest User 2022-01-27T18:52:31Z GL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backup a Custom Configuration</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/backup_custom_configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/backup_custom_configurations/</guid>
      <description>Backup a Custom Configuration Prerequisites Access to the switches. If you are doing a fresh install of CSM but previously had a different version of CSM installed, then you will need to backup/restore certain switch configurations after the switch has been wiped.&#xA;The backup needs to be done before wiping the switch.&#xA;This includes:&#xA;Users and passwords SNMP credentials Site connections Interface speed commands Default routes Any other customized configuration for this system This configuration will likely vary from site to site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remove UAN Access to the CMN</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_disable_uan_vlan7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_disable_uan_vlan7/</guid>
      <description>Remove UAN Access to the CMN To minimize downtime for UANs during an upgrade from CSM 1.0 to CSM 1.2, switch configurations allow UANs to run on both the CSM 1.0 CAN (which becomes the CSM 1.2 CMN) as well as the new CSM 1.2 CAN. At the end of upgrade, switch configurations for UAN ports must be updated to remove the transitionally allowed access of UANs to the CMN. Manual removal of this port access is described in this document.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Customer High Speed Network Routing</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_enable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_enable/</guid>
      <description>Enabling Customer High Speed Network Routing Prerequisites Configuration tasks Configure SLS Configure UAN Minimize UAN downtime Configure UAI Configure compute nodes Retrieve SLS data as JSON Add compute IP addresses to CHN SLS data Upload migrated SLS file to SLS service Enable CFS layer Configure NCNs Configure the API gateways Validation tasks Validating SLS Validating UAN Validating UAI Validate compute nodes Validate NCNs Validate the API gateways Disabling VLAN7 for UANs Prerequisites Many of the procedures use the Cray Command Line Interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BICAN Support Matrix - Shasta Customer Access Networks</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_support_matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_support_matrix/</guid>
      <description>BICAN Support Matrix - Shasta Customer Access Networks Data sheet - Shasta networking - Customer Access Networks Overview Customer Access Networks provide the interface between Shasta system networking and the customer site network. Customer Access Networks (CANs) are routed networks with broadcast domain separation. Customer Access Networks provide higher availability and more flexibility in accessing cloud services compared to traditional &amp;ldquo;bastion hosts&amp;rdquo;, and are more in line with the cloud-native architecture of Shasta as whole.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifurcating the CAN - CSM 1.2 Feature Details</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_details/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_details/</guid>
      <description>Bifurcating the CAN - CSM 1.2 Feature Details CAN new features overview Customer High Speed Network (CHN) CHN system ingress endpoints accessible in CSM 1.2 CHN system egress endpoints accessible in CSM 1.2 Endpoint naming Touchpoints: effects and changes When naming occurs Ability to change post-install Endpoint addressing Touchpoints: effects and changes When addressing occurs Ability to change post-install Traffic separation and routing Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post-install Customer Management Management Network (CMN) Traffic separation and routing Endpoint naming Endpoint addressing Changes Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post-install Customer Access - external/site access Traffic separation and routing Changes Touchpoints: effects and changes When configuration occurs Ability to change post-install 1 CAN new features overview Bifurcation or splitting of the Customer Access Network (CAN) enables customization of customer traffic to and from the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BICAN Summary</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-12/operations/network/management_network/bican_technical_summary/</guid>
      <description>BICAN Summary Bifurcated CAN was designed to separate administrative network traffic and user network traffic.&#xA;BICAN terminology BICAN – Bifurcated Customer Access Network CAN – Customer Access Network CMN – Customer Management Network CHN – Customer High Speed Network NMN – Node Management Network HMN – Hardware Management Network BICAN features Bifurcation or splitting of the Customer Access Network (CAN) enables customization of customer traffic to and from the system. Customization will be performed during installation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
