<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>network on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in network on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-13</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Access to System Management Services</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/access_to_system_management_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/access_to_system_management_services/</guid>
      <description>Access to System Management Services The standard configuration for System Management Services (SMS) is the containerized REST micro-service with a public API. All of the micro-services provide an HTTP interface and are collectively exposed through a single gateway URL. The API gateway for the system is available at a well known URL based on the domain name of the system. It acts as a single HTTPS endpoint for terminating Transport Layer Security (TLS) using the configured certificate authority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Switch over USB-Serial Cable</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/connect_to_switch_over_usb_serial_cable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/connect_to_switch_over_usb_serial_cable/</guid>
      <description>Connect to Switch over USB-Serial Cable In the event that network plumbing is lacking, down, or unconfigured for procuring devices, then it is recommended to use the Serial/COM ports on the management switches.&#xA;This guide will instruct the user on procuring MAC addresses for the NCNs metadata files with the serial console.&#xA;Mileage may vary, as some obstacles such as BAUDRATE and terminal usage vary per manufacturer.&#xA;Common Manufacturers Refer to the external support/documentation portals for more information:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connect to the HPE Cray EX Environment</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/connect_to_the_hpe_cray_ex_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/connect_to_the_hpe_cray_ex_environment/</guid>
      <description>Connect to the HPE Cray EX Environment The HPE Cray EX Management Network (SMNet) has multiple separate physical and logical links that are used to segregate traffic.&#xA;The diagram below shows the available connections from within the SMNet, as well as the connections to the customer network:&#xA;There are multiple ways to connect to the HPE Cray EX environment. The various methods are described in the following table:&#xA;Role Description Administrative External customer network connection to the worker node&amp;rsquo;s hardware management and administrative port Application node access External customer network connection to an Application Node Customer Access Network (CAN) Customer connection to the CAN gateway to access the HPE Cray EX CAN There are also several ways to physically connect to the nodes on the system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a CSM Configuration Upgrade Plan</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/create_a_csm_configuration_upgrade_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/create_a_csm_configuration_upgrade_plan/</guid>
      <description>Create a CSM Configuration Upgrade Plan Creating an upgrade plan is unique and dependent on the requirements of the upgrade path. Some release versions of the network configuration require coupled upgrade of software to enable new software functionality, or bug fixes that may add time required to do the full upgrade.&#xA;For example, in CSM release 1.2, Aruba and Mellanox switches are being upgraded to newer code.&#xA;In this case and cases where configuration changes are extensive, consider taking the generated configurations after review and uploading them to the switches startup config prior to booting to new code to upgrade both configuration and software simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default IP Address Ranges</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/default_ip_address_ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/default_ip_address_ranges/</guid>
      <description>Default IP Address Ranges The initial installation of the system creates default networks with default settings and with no external exposure. These IP address default ranges ensure that no nodes in the system attempt to use the same IP address as a Kubernetes service or pod, which would result in undefined behavior that is extremely difficult to reproduce or debug.&#xA;The following table shows the default IP address ranges:&#xA;Network IP Address Range Kubernetes service network 10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gateway Testing</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/gateway_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/gateway_testing/</guid>
      <description>Gateway Testing With the introduction of BiCAN, service APIs are now available on one or more networks depending on who is allowed access to the services and from where. The services are accessed via three different ingress gateways using a token that can be retrieved from Keycloak.&#xA;This page describes how to run a set of tests that determine if the gateways are functioning properly. The gateway test will obtain an API token from Keycloak and then use that token to attempt to access a set of service APIs on one or more networks, as defined in the gateway test definition file (gateway-test-defn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/operations/network/network/</guid>
      <description>Network There are several different networks supported by the HPE Cray EX system. This page outlines the available internal and external networks, as well as the devices that connect to each network.&#xA;External networks Customer network (data center) System networks Hardware Management Network (HMN) Node Management Network (NMN) ClusterStor Management Network High Speed Network (HSN) IP address ranges Access Control Lists (ACLs) External networks Customer network (data center) The following devices are connected to this network:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
