<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to CSM Installation on Cray System Management (CSM)</title>
    <link>/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction to CSM Installation on Cray System Management (CSM)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-13</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CSM Overview</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/csm_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/csm_overview/</guid>
      <description>CSM Overview This CSM Overview describes the Cray System Management ecosystem with its hardware, software, and network. It describes how to access these services and components.&#xA;The CSM installation prepares and deploys a distributed system across a group of management nodes organized into a Kubernetes cluster which uses Ceph for utility storage. These nodes perform their function as Kubernetes master nodes, Kubernetes worker nodes, or utility storage nodes with the Ceph storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentation Conventions</title>
      <link>/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/documentation_conventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 03:38:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs-csm/en-13/introduction/documentation_conventions/</guid>
      <description>Documentation Conventions This outlines conventions and standards that are used in this documentation.&#xA;Markdown format File formats Typographic conventions Command prompt conventions Host and user name in command prompts Node abbreviations Command prompt reference Command prompt location Command prompts inside new shells chroot example kubectl exec example Combined ssh and chroot example Directory path in command prompt Ability to pause and resume procedures Bad example Good example Markdown format This documentation is in Markdown format.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
